<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<cookbook version="61">
<recipe>
<title>40 Minute Hamburger Buns</title>
<preptime>20 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>12 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 tablespoons active dry yeast</li>
<li>1 cup warm water, plus</li>
<li>2 tablespoons warm water</li>
<li>1/3 cup vegetable oil</li>
<li>1/4 cup sugar</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>3 -3 1/2 cups flour</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1</li>
<li>In a mixing bowl, dissolve yeast in warm water.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2</li>
<li>Add oil and sugar and let stand for 5 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3</li>
<li>Add the egg, salt and enough flour to form a soft dough.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4</li>
<li>Turn onto a floured surface and knead until smooth and elastic, about 3 to 5 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5</li>
<li>Do not let rise.</li>
<li></li>
<li>6</li>
<li>Divide into 12 pieces and shape each into a ball.</li>
<li></li>
<li>7</li>
<li>Place 3&amp;quot; apart on greased baking sheets.</li>
<li></li>
<li>8</li>
<li>Cover and let rest for 10 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>9</li>
<li>Bake at 425° for 8 to 12 minutes or until golden brown.</li>
<li></li>
<li>10</li>
<li>Remove from pans to wire rack to cool.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/40-minute-hamburger-buns-183081</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/40_Minute_Hamburger_Buns.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://img.sndimg.com/food/image/upload/w_266/v1/img/recipes/18/30/81/picdwq659.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 (845 g)</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 195.8 Calories from Fat 62 31% Total Fat 6.9 g 10% Saturated Fat 0.9 g 4% Cholesterol 15.5 mg 5% Sodium 202.0 mg 8% Total Carbohydrate 28.8 g 9% Dietary Fiber 1.3 g 5% Sugars 4.2 g 17% Protein 4.5 g 9%</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>32 mins</totaltime>
<description>Homemade hamburger rolls with only a 10 minute rising time. These are really good. Recipe from Taste of Home.</description>
<source>Marie</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Baked Potato Wedges</title>
<preptime>0H10M</preptime>
<cooktime>0H55M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 large baking potatoes, unpeeled</li>
<li>4 tablespoons good olive oil</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoons kosher salt</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper</li>
<li>1 teaspoon minced fresh garlic</li>
<li>1 teaspoon minced fresh rosemary leaves</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Scrub the potatoes, cut them in half lengthwise, then cut each half in thirds lengthwise. You'll have 6 long wedges from each potato. Place the potatoes on a sheet pan with the olive oil, salt, pepper, garlic, and rosemary. With clean hands, toss all the ingredients together, making sure the potatoes are covered with oil. Spread the potatoes in a single layer with 1 cut-side down.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake the potatoes for 30 to 35 minutes, turning to the other cut side after 20 minutes. Bake until they are lightly browned, crisp outside, and tender inside. Sprinkle with salt and serve.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Copyright 2002 Barefoot Contessa Family Style, All Rights Reserved</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/ina-garten/baked-potato-wedges-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Baked_Potato_Wedges.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://foodnetwork.sndimg.com/content/dam/images/food/fullset/2003/9/29/0/ig1a03_potato_wedges.jpg.rend.sni12col.landscape.jpeg</imageurl>
<quantity>6 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H5M</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Ina Garten</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Sides</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Banana Bread - Quick Bread for Machines</title>
<preptime>15 m</preptime>
<cooktime>50 m</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon baking powder</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon baking soda</li>
<li>3/4 cup white sugar</li>
<li>3 tablespoons vegetable oil</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>2 bananas, peeled and halved lengthwise</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Place ingredients in the pan of the bread machine.</li>
<li>Select the Dough setting, and press Start. Mix the bread for 3 to 5 minutes until the bananas are mashed and all ingredients are thoroughly combined. If necessary, use a rubber spatula to push the dough from the sides of the bread pan. When 3 to 5 minutes have passed on the clock display, press Stop. Do not continue mixing. Smooth out the top of the loaf with the rubber spatula.</li>
<li>Select the Bake setting, and press Start. The Bake cycle time may vary with machines, but should be about 50 minutes. To test the bread for doneness, insert a toothpick into the center top. Remove the toothpick. If the bread is done, the toothpick will come out clean. If there is batter on the toothpick, reset the machine on Bake and continue to bake an additional 10 to 15 minutes. Test again with the toothpick to ensure the bread is completely baked. Remove the pan from the machine, but allow the bread to remain in the pan for 10 minutes. Remove the bread to cool completely on a wire rack.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/7116/banana-bread---quick-bread-for-machines/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Banana_Bread__Quick_Bread_for_Machines.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/59947.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>10</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutrition</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories:</li>
<li></li>
<li>221 kcal</li>
<li></li>
<li>11%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat:</li>
<li></li>
<li>5.4 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>8%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbs:</li>
<li></li>
<li>39.7g</li>
<li></li>
<li>13%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein:</li>
<li></li>
<li>4.1 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>8%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol:</li>
<li></li>
<li>37 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>12%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium:</li>
<li></li>
<li>126 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>5%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Based on a 2,000 calorie diet</li>
<li></li>
<li>See full nutrition</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1 h 15 m</totaltime>
<description>&quot;A quick banana bread for the bread machine. Use the DOUGH setting for mixing, then BAKE with the control set to light.&quot;</description>
<source>Dee</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Basic Cajun Seasoning</title>
<preptime>5 min</preptime>
<cooktime>5 min</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>6 parts salt</li>
<li>1 part cayenne</li>
<li>1 part red pepper</li>
<li>1 part paprika</li>
<li>1 part granulated garlic</li>
<li>1 part grated onion</li>
<li>3/4 part black paprika</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext>mix ingredients</recipetext>
<url></url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>10 serving</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>10min</totaltime>
<description>If the Louisiana Cajun and Creole seasoning Tony Chachere's is not available in a grocery store near you, Patrick Mould offers this recipe to create your own seasoning.</description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Basic Meatballs</title>
<preptime>15 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>20 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 lb ground beef</li>
<li>1 large egg</li>
<li>1⁄4 cup onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>1⁄3 cup Italian seasoned breadcrumbs or 1⁄3 cup old fashioned oats</li>
<li>1⁄4 cup milk</li>
<li>1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce</li>
<li>salt, to taste</li>
<li>fresh ground black pepper, to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Mix ground beef, egg, onion, breadcrumbs, milk, Worcestershire sauce, salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste together.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Shape mixture by Tablespoonfuls into 1-1/2-inch balls.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place the meatballs in a lightly greased 13x9x2-inch or 15-1/2x9-1/2x1-inch baking dish.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake, uncovered, in a 400 degree Fahrenheit oven until light brown, about 20 to 25 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Drain off any excess fat.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Use meatballs as desired.</li>
<li></li>
<li>FREEZING:.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cover and allow meatballs to cool slightly before freezing. No special equipment is needed in the preparation for freezing. Ziplock bags work fine for me. Allow meatballs to thaw about 30 minutes at room temperature before using. Use as desired with your favorite recipes.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/basic-meatballs-8060</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Basic_Meatballs.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://img.sndimg.com/food/image/upload/w_614,h_461,c_fit/v1/img/recipes/80/60/pictMGlyn.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>26-30 meatballs</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Serving Size: 1 (108 g)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 6</li>
<li></li>
<li>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 209.9 Calories from Fat 115 55% Total Fat 12.9 g 19% Saturated Fat 5 g 25% Cholesterol 83.9 mg 27% Sodium 193.4 mg 8% Total Carbohydrate 5.9 g 1% Dietary Fiber 0.4 g 1% Sugars 0.8 g 3% Protein 16.4 g 32%</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>35mins</totaltime>
<description>A snap to make and a breeze to freeze! This is a basic recipe for meatballs suitable for all uses. Feel free to be creative and add any additional spices or flavors you need to suit your tastes.</description>
<source>- Carla -</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Italian</category>
<category>Entree</category>
<category>Meats</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Basic Soft White Sandwich Loaf</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>Dough Starter (Sponge)</li>
<li>unbleached all-purpose flour (use only Gold Medal, King Arthur, or Pillsbury): 2 1/4 cups plus 2 1/2 tablespoons (12 ounces or 341 grams)</li>
<li>water, at room temperature (70° to 90°F) : scant 1 3/4 liquid cups (14.3 ounces or 405 grams)</li>
<li>honey: 2 tablespoons plus 1 teaspoon (1.5 ounces or 45 grams)</li>
<li>instant yeast: 3/4 teaspoon (2.4 grams)</li>
<li>Equipment</li>
<li>two 8 1/2-in-4 1/2-inch loaf pans, lightly greased with cooking spray or oil</li>
<li>a baking stone OR baking sheet</li>
<li>Flour Mixture and Dough</li>
<li>unbleached all-purpose flour (use only Gold Medal, King Arthur, or Pillsbury): 2 cups plus 3 tablespoons (about 11 ounces or 311 grams)</li>
<li>dry milk, preferably nonfat: 1/4 cup (1.5 or 40 grams)</li>
<li>instant yeast: 3/4 teaspoon (2.4 grams)</li>
<li>unsalted butter, softened: 9 tablespoons (4.5 ounces or 128 grams)</li>
<li>salt: 2 1/4 teaspoons (15 grams)</li>
<li>Optional: melted butter: 1 tablespoon (0.5 ounces or 14 grams)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Make the sponge. In a mixer bowl or other large bowl, combine the flour, water, honey, and instant yeast. Whisk until very smooth, to incorporate air, about 2 minutes. The sponge will be the consistency of a thick batter, Scrape down the sides of the bowl, and cover with plastic wrap.</li>
<li>2. Make the flour mixture and add to the sponge. In a medium bowl, whisk together the flour (reserve 1/4 cup if mixing by hand), dry milk, and instant yeast. Sprinkle this on top of the sponge and cover tightly with plastic wrap. Allow it to ferment for 1 to 4 hours at room temperature. (During this time, the sponge will bubble through the flour blanket in places: this is fine.)</li>
<li>3. Mix the dough.</li>
<li>Mixer Method</li>
<li>Add the butter to the bowl and mix with the dough hook on low speed (#2 if using a KitchenAid) for 1 minute or until the flour is moistened enough to form a rough dough. Scrape down any bits of dough. Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and allow the dough to rest for 20 minutes.</li>
<li>Sprinkle on the salt and knead the dough on medium speed (#4 KitchenAid) for 7 to 10 minutes. It will not come away from the bowl until the last minute or so of kneading; it will be smooth and shiny and stick to your fingers. With an oiled spatula, scrape down any dough clinging to the sides of the bowl. If the dough is not stiff, knead in a little flour. If it is not at all sticky, spray it with a little water and knead it in. (The dough will weigh about 44.25 ounces/1258 grams.)</li>
<li>Hand Method</li>
<li>Add the salt and butter to the bowl and, with a wooden spoon or your hand, stir until all the flour is moistened. Knead the dough in the bowl until it comes together, then scrape it onto a lightly floured counter. Knead the dough for 5 minutes, enough to develop the gluten structure a little, adding as little of the reserved flour as possible to keep the dough from sticking. Use a bench scraper to scrape the dough and gather it together as you knead it. At this point, it will be very sticky. Cover it with the inverted bowl and allow it to rest for 20 minutes. (This resting time will make the dough less sticky and easier to work with.)</li>
<li>Knead the dough for another 5 minutes or until it is very smooth and elastic. It should still be tacky (sticky) enough to cling slightly to your fingers a little. If the dough is still very sticky, however, add some of the remaining reserved flour, or a little extra. (The dough will weigh about 44.25 ounces/1258 grams.)</li>
<li>Both Methods</li>
<li>4. Let the dough rise. Using an oiled spatula or dough scraper, scrape the dough into a 4-quart dough-rising container or bowl, lightly oiled with cooking spray or oil. Push down the dough and lightly spray or oil the surface. Cover the container with a lid or plastic wrap. With a piece of tape, mark the side of the container at approximately where double the height of the dough would be. Allow the dough to rise (ideally at 75°to 80°F) until doubled, 1 1/2 to 2 hours.</li>
<li>Using an oiled spatula or dough scraper, scrape the dough onto a floured counter and press down on it gently to form a rectangle. It will be full of air and resilient. Try to maintain as many of the air bubbles as possible. Pull out and fold the dough over from all four sides into a tight package, or give it 2 business letter turns and set it back in the container. Again oil the surface, cover, and mark where double the height would now be. (It will fill the container fuller than before because it is puffier with air.) Allow the dough to rise for 1 to 2 hours or until it reaches the mark.</li>
<li>5. Shape the dough and let it rise. Turn the dough out onto a lightly floured counter and cut it in half. Shape each piece into a loaf: begin by gently pressing the dough (or lightly rolling it with a rolling pin) into a wide rectangle; the exact size is not important at this point. (A long side of the dough should be facing toward you.) Dimple the dough with your fingertips to deflate any large bubbles. Fold over the right side of the dough to a little past the center. Fold over the left side of the dough to overlap it slightly. Press the center overlap section with the side of your hand to seal the dough. (If you have a lot of experience shaping, you may prefer at this point to rotate the dough 90 degrees-a quarter turn.) Starting at the top edge of the dough, roll it over three or four times, until it reaches the bottom edge of the dough: with each roll, press with your thumbs to seal it and at the same time push it away from you slightly to tighten the outer skin. As you roll and press, the dough will become wider. If it is not as long as the pan, place both hands close together on top of the dough and, rolling back and forth, gradually work your way toward the ends, gently stretching the dough. For the most even shape, it is important to keep a tight skin on the surface of the dough and not to tear it. If you want the edges of the loaf to be smooth, tuck the sides under.</li>
<li>Place the loaves in the prepared loaf pans; the dough will be about 1/2 inch from the top of the pans. Cover them with a large container, or cover them loosely with oiled plastic wrap, and allow to rise until the center is about 1 inch above the sides of the pan, 1 1/2 to 2 hours. When the dough is pressed with a fingertip, the depression will very slowly fill in.</li>
<li>6. Preheat the oven. Preheat the oven to 350°F 45 minutes before baking. Have an oven shelf at the lowest level and place a baking stone or baking sheet on it, and a cast-iron skillet or sheet pan on the floor of the oven, before preheating.</li>
<li>7. Bake the bread. Quickly but gently set the pans on the hot baking stone or hot baking sheet. Toss 1/2 cup of ice cubes into the pan beneath and immediately shut the door. Bake for 50 minutes or until medium golden brown and a skewer inserted in the middle comes out clean (an instant-read thermometer inserted into the center will read about 210°F). Halfway through baking, turn the pans around for even baking.</li>
<li>8. Glaze and cool the bread. Remove the bread from the oven and set it on a wire rack. Brush the top of the bread with the optional melted butter. Unmold and cool top side up on a wire rack until barely warm, about 1 hour.</li>
<li>ULTIMATE FULL FLAVOR VARIATION</li>
<li>For the best flavor development, in Step 2, allow the sponge to ferment for 1 hour at room temperature and then refrigerate it for 8 to 24 hours. If using the hand mixing method, remove it from the refrigerator about 1 hour before mixing the dough.</li>
<li>POINTERS FOR SUCCESS</li>
<li>• If not using the dry milk, you can replace 1 cup of the water with 1 cup milk, preferably nonfat, scalded (brought to the boiling point) and cooled to lukewarm.</li>
<li>UNDERSTANDING</li>
<li>A greater amount of sponge dough starter (pre-ferment) offers a fuller flavor in this &quot;plain&quot; bread, so almost 50 percent of total amount of flour is used in the sponge, compared to the usual 30 percent of hearth breads.</li>
<li>If using liquid milk, it is scalded to deactivate the enzyme in it that could make the dough sticky.</li>
<li>Baking the bread at too high a temperature, would result in too thin a crust, which would cause keyholing, or caving in at the sides of the loaf. Therefore, this bread is baked at 350°F. It is also important for the bread to be thoroughly baked so that the crust is firm enough to prevent it from compressing. The loaves should not be cut until completely cool for the same reason.</li>
<li>THE DOUGH PERCENTAGE</li>
<li>Flour: 100%</li>
<li>Water: 66.3% (includes the water in the butter and honey)</li>
<li>Yeast: 0.74%</li>
<li>Salt: 2.3%</li>
<li>Butterfat: 15.9%</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/basic-soft-white-sandwich-loaf-351269</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Basic_Soft_White_Sandwich_Loaf.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://assets.epicurious.com/photos/5609a4cf6a59cdb91b5ff390/1:1/w_600%2Ch_600/351269.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Makes: two 8-by-4-by-4 1/2-inch-high loaves (1 1/4 pounds/581 grams)</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description><li>This is my best white bread for sandwiches, dinner rolls, cinnamon swirl or herb swirl breads, and toast. I developed it to match my childhood memory of my favorite bread, Silvercup, a soft, light, and airy bread like today's Wonder Bread, which made the best toast. This homemade version has the same texture but has a more yeasty and fuller flavor. In fact, this bread is like a brioche, with less butter and no egg. It has an even yet open crumb but is softer and lighter in texture. Part of the secret of its light texture is that, like brioche, it is made from an exceptionally moist dough. Lightly toasted and topped with soft scrambled eggs, it is nothing short of ambrosial. Michael Batterberry, publisher of Food Arts magazine, tasted this bread and said, &quot;Mmmm. . . . This is what Wonder Bread, in its soul, really always wanted to be!&quot;</li>
<li></li>
<li>TIME SCHEDULE</li>
<li>Dough Starter (Sponge): minimum 1 hour, maximum 24 hours</li>
<li>Minimum Rising Time: about 4 hours</li>
<li>Oven Temperature: 350°F</li>
<li>Baking Time: 50 minutes</li>
</description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Baking</category>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Basic White Bread</title>
<preptime>5 minutes</preptime>
<cooktime>as per bread machine</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>Large Loaf (1½ lb/3 cup or 2 lb/4 cup machine)</li>
<li>1¼ cups (300 mL) water</li>
<li>2 tbsp (30 mL) butter</li>
<li>3 cups (750 mL) Robin Hood® Best for Bread Homestyle White Flour</li>
<li>Robin Hood® Best For Bread Homestyle White Flour</li>
<li>2 tbsp (30 mL) granulated sugar</li>
<li>1½ tsp (7 mL) salt</li>
<li>1½ tsp (7 mL) bread machine yeast</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Select loaf size.</li>
<li>Add ingredients to machine according to manufacturer’s directions.</li>
<li>Select White Cycle.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.robinhood.ca/Recipes/Bread-Machine/White-Breads/Basic-White-Bread-machine</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Basic_White_Bread.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.smuckers.ca/images/recipes/17/basic-white-bread-machine.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 loaf</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information Servings Per Recipe Per 2 slices (96 g)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories 251</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 8.9 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat 3 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 1.6 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbohydrate 47 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fibre 1.4 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 309 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 7 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A 3 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin C 0 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calcium 2 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Iron 16 %</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description>No dissolving, stirring or kneading is required with this mouth-watering recipe. Just measure the ingredients, place them in your bread machine, select the cycle and start working up your appetite.</description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Baking</category>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Bavarian Soft Pretzels</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 packet active dry bread yeast</li>
<li>1 c warm water</li>
<li>2 tb soft butter or margarine</li>
<li>2 3/4 c bread flour</li>
<li>1/2 t salt</li>
<li>1 tb sugar</li>
<li>5 t baking soda (for glazing)</li>
<li>Coarse salt (if desired)</li>
<li></li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>- In a large mixing bowl, combine 1 cup warm water and packet of yeast.</li>
<li></li>
<li>- Mix in 1-1/2 cups of flower, the 2 tblsp margarine, 1/2 tsp salt and 1tblsp sugar. Beat the entire mixture for 3 minutes to mix well.</li>
<li></li>
<li>- Slowly mix in the remaining 1-1/4 cups of flour, and knead dough until all of the flour is mixed in and dough loses its stickiness.</li>
<li></li>
<li>- Set aside in bowl, and let it rise until dough reaches approximately double its original size.</li>
<li></li>
<li>- Divide dough into twelve approximately equal pieces. Using your palms, roll each piece into 18″ lengths about pencil thickness. Loop</li>
<li>and twist the lengths into pretzel shapes and place on a greased baking sheet. Allow pretzels to rise again until they approximately double in girth.</li>
<li></li>
<li>- Preheat oven to 475 degrees, and ready a boiling solution of 4 cups of water, and the 5 tsp of baking soda in a shallow non-aluminum (note</li>
<li>– aluminum may react with baking soda).</li>
<li></li>
<li>- With a plastic spatula, carefully lift each pretzel from the sheet</li>
<li>and lower it into the boiling baking soda solution for 15-20 seconds.</li>
<li>This will glaze the pretzels once you bake them.</li>
<li></li>
<li>- Sprinkle the pretzels with coarse salt (if desired, they’re great without salt as well), and bake approximately 7-10 minutes until browned. Serve warm, topped with mustard or cheese, and a pint of your favorite beer.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>MMF</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>1</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Sides</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Beautiful Burger Buns</title>
<preptime>25 mins.</preptime>
<cooktime>15 mins.</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3/4 to 1 cup lukewarm water</li>
<li>2 tablespoons butter</li>
<li>1 large egg</li>
<li>3 1/2 cups King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour</li>
<li>1/4 cup sugar</li>
<li>1 1/4 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1 tablespoon instant yeast</li>
<li>*For best results (a smooth, slightly soft dough), use the smaller amount of water in summer (or in a humid environment), the greater amount in winter (or in a dry climate); and something in between the rest of the time.</li>
<li>3 tablespoons melted butter</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1) Mix and knead all of the dough ingredients — by hand, mixer, or bread machine — to make a soft, smooth dough.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2) Cover the dough, and let it rise for 1 to 2 hours, or until it's nearly doubled in bulk.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3) Gently deflate the dough, and divide it into 8 pieces. Shape each piece into a round ball; flatten to about 3&quot; across. Place the buns on a lightly greased or parchment-lined baking sheet, cover, and let rise for about an hour, until noticeably puffy.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4) Brush the buns with about half of the melted butter.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5) Bake the buns in a preheated 375°F oven for 15 to 18 minutes, until golden. Remove them from the oven, and brush with the remaining melted butter. This will give the buns a satiny, buttery crust.</li>
<li></li>
<li>6) Cool the buns on a rack.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Yield: 8 large buns.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.kingarthurflour.com/recipes/beautiful-burger-buns-recipe</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Beautiful_Burger_Buns.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.kingarthurflour.com/shop-img/1323116369737.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 buns</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition>Serving Size: 1 bun (99g) Servings Per Batch: 8 Amount Per Serving: Calories: 250 Calories from Fat: 35 Total Fat: 4g Saturated Fat: 2g Trans Fat: 0g Cholesterol: 30mg Sodium: 370mg Total Carbohydrate: 45g Dietary Fiber: 2g Sugars: 7g Protein: 8g</nutrition>
<comments><li>For slightly smaller buns, divide the dough into 12 pieces instead of 8. Bake the buns for 12 to 15 minutes, instead of 15 to 18 minutes. And how about &quot;slider buns&quot; — about 3&quot; in diameter? Divide the dough into 24 pieces, and bake for 12 to 15 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>When making anything with yeast, including these rolls, let the dough rise to the point the recipe says it should, e.g., &quot;Let the dough rise till it's doubled in bulk.&quot; Rising times are only a guide; there are so many variables in yeast baking (how you knead the dough; what kind of yeast you use) that it's impossible to say that bread dough will ALWAYS double in bulk in a specific amount of time.</li>
<li></li>
<li>What's another easy way to shape buns, besides rolling them into balls and flattening? Gently deflate the dough, and form it into a smooth 8&quot; log. Slice the log as though you were slicing cinnamon buns. Gently pull each slice into a circle.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Brushing buns with melted butter will give them a soft, light golden crust. Brushing with an egg-white wash (1 egg white beaten with 1/4 cup water) will give them a shinier, darker crust. For seeded buns, brush with the egg wash; it'll make the seeds adhere. And, feel free to add the extra yolk to the dough, reserving the white for the wash.</li>
</comments>
<totaltime>2 hrs 40 mins.</totaltime>
<description><li>The following recipe created quite a stir when it was first posted on our original online community. Baker after baker tried these buns and declared them THE BEST. Soft, vaguely sweet and golden-yellow from the butter and egg, these simple buns are perfect for burgers, but also fine for any kind of sandwich.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Credit for the original version of this recipe goes to &quot;Moomie&quot; (Ellen), one of the original members of our online community, The Baking Circle. Thanks, Moomie, for the joy you've brought to bun-lovers everywhere!</li>
</description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Beef 'n' Pork Burgers</title>
<preptime>15M</preptime>
<cooktime>10M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 bacon strips, diced</li>
<li>1 large onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 garlic clove, minced</li>
<li>1-1/2 cups soft bread crumbs</li>
<li>1 large egg, lightly beaten</li>
<li>1/2 cup water</li>
<li>1 tablespoon dried parsley flakes</li>
<li>2 to 3 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried marjoram</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon pepper</li>
<li>1 pound ground beef</li>
<li>1 pound ground pork</li>
<li>8 hamburger buns, split and toasted</li>
<li>Mayonnaise, lettuce leaves and tomato slices</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>In a small skillet, cook bacon, onion and garlic over medium heat until the bacon is crisp; drain and place in a small bowl. Stir in the bread crumbs, egg, water, parsley, salt, marjoram, paprika and pepper. Crumble beef and pork over the mixture and mix well. Shape into eight 3/4-in.-thick patties.</li>
<li>Grill, uncovered, over medium-hot heat for 4-5 minutes on each side or until a thermometer reads 160°. Serve on buns with mayonnaise, lettuce and tomato. Yield: 8 servings.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.tasteofhome.com/recipes/beef--n--pork-burgers</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Beef_n_Pork_Burgers.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://cdn1.tmbi.com/TOH/Images/Photos/37/300x300/exps18404_GAC1115479D53A.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition>1 each: 412 calories, 20g fat (7g saturated fat), 105mg cholesterol, 992mg sodium, 28g carbohydrate (5g sugars, 2g fiber), 28g protein</nutrition>
<comments>The combination of ground beef and pork is the secret behind these juicy burgers. The never-fail burgers are ideal for summer grilling, so I depend on them time and again. Everyone loves them. Plus, you can easily double or triple the recipe for large get-togethers.—Sharon Adamczyk, Wind Lake, Wisconsin</comments>
<totaltime>25M</totaltime>
<description>The combination of ground beef and pork is the secret behind these juicy burgers. The never-fail burgers are ideal for summer grilling, so I depend on them time and again. Everyone loves them. Plus, you can easily double or triple the recipe for large get-togethers.—Sharon Adamczyk, Wind Lake, Wisconsin</description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Entree</category>
<category>Meats</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Best Bread Machine Bread</title>
<preptime>10M</preptime>
<cooktime>40M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 cup warm water (110 degrees F/45 degrees C)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Barley Malt Syrup</li>
<li>or 2 tablespoons white sugar</li>
<li>1 (.25 ounce) package bread machine yeast</li>
<li>1/4 cup vegetable oil</li>
<li>3 cups bread flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Place the water, sugar and yeast in the pan of the bread machine. Let the yeast dissolve and foam for 10 minutes. Add the oil, flour and salt to the yeast. Select Basic or White Bread setting, and press Start.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/best-bread-machine-bread/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Best_Bread_Machine_Bread.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/00/07/12/71260.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 - 1 1/2 pound loaf</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Best Bread Machine Bread</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/12 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 12</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 174</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 47</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 5.2g 8 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 0.7g 3 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 0mg 0 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 195mg 8 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Potassium 46mg 1 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Carbohydrates 27.1g 9 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dietary Fiber 0.9g 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 4.3g 9 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sugars 2.2g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>3H</totaltime>
<description>&quot;This recipe is easy and foolproof. It makes a very soft and tasty loaf of bread with a flaky crust.&quot;</description>
<source>SHECOOKS2</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/710/bread-machine-bread/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Better No-Knead Bread</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>300 grams (10.5 ounces, about 2 cups) bread flour or all-purpose flour</li>
<li>4.5 grams (about 3/4 teaspoon) salt</li>
<li>3 grams (about .5 taspoons) yeast</li>
<li>210 grams (7.5 ounces, about 1 cup minus 1.5 tablespoons) water</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Combine flour, salt, and yeast in a large bowl and whisk to combine. Add water and stir with a wooden spoon until no dry flour remains. Cover bowl tightly with plastic wrap and let sit at room temperature for at least 12 and up to 24 hours.</li>
<li>Transfer container to refrigerator and let sit for at least 3 and up to 5 days.</li>
<li>Remove dough from refrigerator and turn out onto well-floured surface. Turn once or twice and form into loaf shape. Cover with a well-floured kitchen towel and allow to rise at room temperature for at least two hours, and up to 4.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, adjust oven rack to lower middle position and preheat oven to 450°F, with a heavy cast-iron or stainless steel Dutch oven placed inside it.</li>
<li>When dough has risen, slash top with a floured knife into two or three slashes, 1/2 inch deep. Remove Dutch oven from oven and working quickly, drop dough inside. Place lid back on Dutch oven and return to oven. Bake for 15 minutes, then remove lid and continue to bake until center of bread registers 209°F on an instant read thermometer, about 30 to 45 minutes longer (time will vary depending on shape of loaf).</li>
<li>Remove Dutch oven from oven and remove loaf of bread with a spatula or tongs. Allow to rest on a wire rack for at least 15 minutes before slicing and serving. Unused bread can be stored at room temperature wrapped in foil for up to three days, though it may need to be refreshed in a hot oven or toaster before serving.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2011/06/better-no-knead-bread-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Better_NoKnead_Bread.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/assets_c/2011/06/20110617-no-knead-bread-primary-thumb-625xauto-167152.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Makes 1 loaf, serving 4 to 6</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description><li>This recipe appears in: Serious Entertaining: The Vegan, One Meal Convince-A-Meathead Challenge The Food Lab: The Science of No-Knead Dough</li>
<li></li>
<li>Note: You can modify this recipe easily to bake loaves of any size. The important thing to note is the ratio of ingredients: 100 parts flour, 1.5 parts salt, 1 part instant yeast, and 70 parts water.</li>
</description>
<source>J. Kenji López-Alt</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Boston Baked Beans in Bean Pot - Durgin-Park</title>
<preptime>30 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>6 hrs</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 lb dried navy beans (see NOTE)</li>
<li>1⁄2 teaspoon baking soda</li>
<li>1⁄2 lb salt pork</li>
<li>1⁄2 medium onion (peeled and uncut)</li>
<li>4 tablespoons sugar</li>
<li>1⁄3 cup molasses</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dry mustard</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1⁄4 teaspoon pepper</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>NOTE: Use navy beans, California pea beans, or small white beans.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Soak beans overnight.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In the morning, preheat oven to 325°F Place the baking soda in a Dutch oven and fill half way with water.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bring to a boil, add the beans &amp; boil for 10 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Drain beans in a colander and run cold water through them. Set aside.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dice the salt pork (available in the bacon section of the grocery store)into 1-inch squares.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Put half of the salt pork on the bottom of the bean pot, along with the onion.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Put beans in the pot.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Put the remaining salt pork on top of the beans.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Mix the sugar, molasses, mustard, salt and pepper with 3 cups of hot water and pour over the beans.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cover pot with lid and place the pot into the preheated oven.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake for 6 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Check pot periodically to make sure the amount of liquid is okay.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add water to the beans slowly as needed to keep them moist; DO NOT FLOOD THEM. Just &quot;top them up&quot;.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Remove the pot from the oven and serve.</li>
<li></li>
<li>NOTE: The Durgin-Park, a Boston restaurant whose origins date back to the American Revolution, is famous for its Boston baked beans, baked Indian pudding and apple pan dowdy. Durgin-Park cook Tommy Ryan has prepared this recipe at the restaurant for the past 37 years.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Durgin-Park serves 1,000 diners on an average Saturday evening. The waitresses have a reputation for their long memories: the second time you come in, you get the same thing you ordered the first time--unless you speak fast.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/boston-baked-beans-in-bean-pot-durgin-park-168437</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Boston_Baked_Beans_in_Bean_Pot__DurginPark.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://img.sndimg.com/food/image/upload/w_614,h_461,c_fit/v1/img/recipes/16/84/37/picXCECPY.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>7 cups</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Serving Size: 1 (909 g)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 1</li>
<li></li>
<li>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 540.3 Calories from Fat 244 45% Total Fat 27.2 g 41% Saturated Fat 9.6 g 48% Cholesterol 27.9 mg 9% Sodium 893.5 mg 37% Total Carbohydrate 59.4 g 19% Dietary Fiber 16 g 64% Sugars 19 g 75% Protein 16.3 g 32%</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>6hrs 30mins</totaltime>
<description>PLEASE DO not ADD ANYTHING OR CHANGE ANYTHING ABOUT THIS RECIPE. To do so means you will not be tasting The Durgin Park recipe but your own variation of it. NOT FAIR. Sorry. I appreciate that some of you have tried this recipe with your own additions but please, you are NOT reviewing MY/Durgin Park's recipe but your own! These, of course, are the ultimate Boston Baked Beans! Please take into account they need to soak overnight. You will need a 2 1/2-quart bean pot or covered casserole. Recipe By: Durgin-Park Restaurant, Boston, MA</description>
<source>Nana Lee</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Baking</category>
<category>Sides</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Bread Machine Bagels</title>
<preptime>30 m</preptime>
<cooktime>3 h 25 m</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 cup warm water (110 degrees F/45 degrees C)</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>2 tablespoons white sugar</li>
<li>3 cups bread flour</li>
<li>2 1/4 teaspoons active dry yeast</li>
<li>3 quarts boiling water</li>
<li>3 tablespoons white sugar</li>
<li>1 tablespoon cornmeal</li>
<li>1 egg white</li>
<li>3 tablespoons poppy seeds</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Place water, salt, sugar, flour and yeast in the bread machine pan in the order recommended by the manufacturer. Select Dough setting.</li>
<li>When cycle is complete, let dough rest on a lightly floured surface. Meanwhile, in a large pot bring 3 quarts of water to a boil. Stir in 3 tablespoons of sugar.</li>
<li>Cut dough into 9 equal pieces, and roll each piece into a small ball. Flatten balls. Poke a hole in the middle of each with your thumb. Twirl the dough on your finger or thumb to enlarge the hole, and to even out the dough around the hole. Cover bagels with a clean cloth, and let rest for 10 minutes.</li>
<li>Sprinkle an ungreased baking sheet with cornmeal. Carefully transfer bagels to boiling water. Boil for 1 minute, turning half way through. Drain briefly on clean towel. Arrange boiled bagels on baking sheet. Glaze tops with egg white, and sprinkle with your choice of toppings.</li>
<li>Bake in a preheated 375 degree F (190 degrees C) oven for 20 to 25 minutes, until well browned.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/7178/bread-machine-bagels/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Bread_Machine_Bagels.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/68073.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>9</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutrition</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories:</li>
<li></li>
<li>215 kcal</li>
<li></li>
<li>11%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat:</li>
<li></li>
<li>2.1 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>3%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbs:</li>
<li></li>
<li>41.9g</li>
<li></li>
<li>14%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein:</li>
<li></li>
<li>6.8 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>14%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol:</li>
<li></li>
<li>0 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>0%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium:</li>
<li></li>
<li>405 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>16%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Based on a 2,000 calorie diet</li>
<li></li>
<li>See full nutrition</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>3 h 55 m</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Quick and easy bagels you can make with your bread machine! You can use whatever topping that you wish, many like poppy seeds.&quot;</description>
<source>Cristy Chu</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Bread Machine Bread — Easy As Can Be</title>
<preptime>5 mins. to 10 mins.</preptime>
<cooktime>60 mins. to 60 mins.</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 cup lukewarm water</li>
<li>1/3 cup lukewarm milk</li>
<li>3 tablespoons butter</li>
<li>3 3/4 cups King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour</li>
<li>3 tablespoons sugar</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoons active dry yeast or instant yeast</li>
<li>2/3 cup lukewarm water</li>
<li>1/4 cup lukewarm milk</li>
<li>2 tablespoons butter</li>
<li>2 1/2 cups King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour</li>
<li>5 teaspoons sugar</li>
<li>1 1/4 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon active dry yeast or instant yeast</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Put all of the ingredients into your machine in the order recommended by the manufacturer.</li>
<li>Program the machine for basic white bread, and press Start.</li>
<li>When the loaf is done, remove the pan from the machine. After about 5 minutes, gently shake the pan to dislodge the loaf, and turn it out onto a rack to cool.</li>
<li>Store, well-wrapped, on the counter for 4 days, or freeze for up to 3 months.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.kingarthurflour.com/recipes/bread-machine-bread-easy-as-can-be-recipe</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Bread_Machine_Bread__Easy_As_Can_Be.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://d2gk7xgygi98cy.cloudfront.net/5735-4-facebook.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 loaf</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>2 hrs 20 mins. to 3 hrs 25 mins.</totaltime>
<description>King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour is perfect for bread machines. Its high protein level (11.7 grams per cup), and the quality of that protein, allows you to use it in recipes calling for either bread flour or all-purpose flour. This recipe makes a reliably high-rising loaf, with soft, springy texture and nicely balanced flavor.</description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Baking</category>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Cajun Seasoning</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>6 tablespoons paprika</li>
<li>1/4 cup kosher salt</li>
<li>2 tablespoons ground black pepper</li>
<li>2 tablespoons ground white pepper</li>
<li>2 tablespoons garlic powder</li>
<li>2 tablespoons onion powder</li>
<li>1 tablespoon dried thyme</li>
<li>1 tablespoon cayenne</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext>1Combine paprika, salt, black pepper, white pepper, garlic powder, onion powder, dried thyme, and cayenne.</recipetext>
<url>http://www.chow.com/recipes/10567-cajun-seasoning</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Cajun_Seasoning.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://search.chow.com/thumbnail/1600/0/www.chowstatic.com/assets/2007/01/cajun_rub.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>About 1 1/4 cups</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description>Hot, peppery Cajun seasoning is essential for Cajun-style blackened fish or chicken.</description>
<source>Aliza Green</source>
<video></video>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Cajun Spice Mix</title>
<preptime>5 m</preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>2 teaspoons garlic powder</li>
<li>2 1/2 teaspoons paprika</li>
<li>1 teaspoon ground black pepper</li>
<li>1 teaspoon onion powder</li>
<li>1 teaspoon cayenne pepper</li>
<li>1 1/4 teaspoons dried oregano</li>
<li>1 1/4 teaspoons dried thyme</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon red pepper flakes (optional)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext>Stir together salt, garlic powder, paprika, black pepper, onion powder, cayenne pepper, oregano, thyme, and red pepper flakes until evenly blended. Store in an airtight container.</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/149221/cajun-spice-mix/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Cajun_Spice_Mix.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/720x405/606314.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>12</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>1 Serving</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe:</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>* Percent Daily Values are based on a 2,000 calorie diet. Your daily values may be higher or lower depending on your calorie needs.</li>
<li></li>
<li>** Nutrient information is not available for all ingredients. Amount is based on available nutrient data.</li>
<li></li>
<li>(-) Information is not currently available for this nutrient. If you are following a medically restrictive diet, please consult your doctor or registered dietitian before preparing this recipe for personal consumption.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Hide full nutrition</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>5 m</totaltime>
<description>See how to make a mildly hot Cajun spice mix…for just about anything!</description>
<source>Bobbie Buckley Dirks</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Chicago Style Deep Dish Sausage Pizza - Real Deep Dish</title>
<preptime>2 hrs 18 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>35 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3⁄4 cup water, lukewarm 110 degrees F</li>
<li>1⁄4 teaspoon granulated sugar</li>
<li>1⁄4 teaspoon sea salt or 1⁄4 teaspoon table salt</li>
<li>1⁄2 teaspoon active dry yeast</li>
<li>1⁄4 cup corn oil</li>
<li>2 1⁄4 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>nonstick cooking spray (for greasing your pan)</li>
<li>12 ounces mozzarella cheese, sliced (low moisture, approximately 15 slices)</li>
<li>3⁄4 lb Italian sausage, raw</li>
<li>16 ounces crushed tomatoes, lightly drained</li>
<li>1⁄8 cup romano cheese, grated or 1⁄8 cup parmesan cheese</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>MAKING THE DOUGH: In a mixing bowl, dissolve sugar and salt into the lukewarm water.</li>
<li>Add yeast, corn oil, and a small amount of the flour.</li>
<li>Mix until you have a thick batter, then add the rest of the flour and continue mixing until combined.</li>
<li>Knead until the dough comes together into a smooth ball, then STOP. DON’T OVER-KNEAD. Total mixing/kneading time should be no more than 2 - 3 minutes (This step can also be done in a mixer with a dough hook in 1 - 2 minutes. If it looks smooth, but doesn’t form a ball, just take it off the hook and form into a ball).</li>
<li>Place the dough in a bowl (or keep it in your mixing bowl), lightly oil/spray the dough ball.</li>
<li>Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and place in a warm place. Let the dough rise for 1 to 2 hours (or until dough has doubled).</li>
<li>After the rise, you can use the dough immediately OR punch down the dough and let it rise again until you’re ready to use the dough OR place it into a plastic zip-top bag and into the refrigerator for 6 to 24 hours.</li>
<li>ASSEMBLING YOUR PIZZA AND BAKING: Place a pizza stone in the bottom rack of your oven and place a sheet of heavy duty aluminum foil across the top rack. Preheat your oven to 500 degrees (F). It should take about 40 minutes to an hour to preheat your stone, so you may want to do this while your dough is rising. If you refrigerated your dough, take it out of the fridge while your oven is preheating.</li>
<li>Using a fine mesh strainer over a bowl, drain any excess liquid from your tomatoes, if necessary.</li>
<li>Lightly grease the bottom (not the sides) of your pan with oil or high-heat cooking spray.</li>
<li>Press out the dough in the pan from center to the edge, as flat and even as possible. Pinch up the sides into a paper-thin lip about 1 to 1-1/2 inches high.</li>
<li>Lightly press sliced mozzarella cheese into the dough, overlapping the slices until the entire bottom is covered (If making an all-cheese pizza, you can add extra cheese if you want, then skip to the part where you add the tomatoes).</li>
<li>Add the Italian sausage: For traditional patty, add small bits of sausage on top of the cheese, connecting the bits together into a loose web, until the entire bottom is covered.</li>
<li>Add any other ingredient that you want to protect from burning.</li>
<li>THE PART WHERE YOU ADD THE TOMATOES: With a large spoon or ladle, top the pizza with the crushed tomatoes, spreading the sauce from the center out to the edge until the other ingredients are completely covered with sauce. You should need between 14 and 16 oz of tomatoes.</li>
<li>Sprinkle grated Romano (and/or Parmesan) Cheese over the top of the sauce.</li>
<li>Turn oven down to 450 and place the pizza pan directly on top of the pizza stone on the lower rack.</li>
<li>Bake for approximately 35 minutes. If your crust or toppings start to char on top, place a loose sheet of aluminum foil over the top of the pizza for the remaining baking time.</li>
<li>Remove from oven, let pizza rest for 5 minutes, then cut &amp; serve on a real plate with a knife &amp; fork.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/chicago-style-deep-dish-sausage-pizza-real-deep-dish-512553?photo=354364</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Chicago_Style_Deep_Dish_Sausage_Pizza__Real_Deep_Dish.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://img.sndimg.com/food/image/upload/w_614,h_461,c_fit/v1/img/recipes/51/25/53/mCNDhtRORXu5TfNkltCo_image.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 Deep Dish Pizza</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Serving Size: 1 (277 g)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 6</li>
<li></li>
<li>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 649.4 Calories from Fat 346 53% Total Fat 38.5 g 59% Saturated Fat 14.5 g 72% Cholesterol 79.1 mg 26% Sodium 1261.1 mg 52% Total Carbohydrate 45.3 g 15% Dietary Fiber 2.9 g 11% Sugars 1.4 g 5% Protein 30.2 g 60%</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>2hrs 53mins</totaltime>
<description>READ THIS FIRST: This recipe should help you achieve the best deep-dish pizza you will ever bake at home. Instructions are for making a 12&quot; deep dish pizza. Please take the time to read through the entire recipe before you start. Also, it will help greatly if you have the following baking equipment: 1 round deep-dish pizza/cake pan - 12” diameter by 2” in height, 1 Pizza Stone (optional, but recommended - place on bottom oven rack), Fine mesh Strainer and Bowl (for draining excess liquid from tomatoes), Large Spoon or Ladle (for spreading tomato sauce.), Sturdy mixing spoon, Stainless Steel/Plastic Bowl, and food service gloves (for kneading - optional), a wide roll of heavy duty aluminum foil, Pan Gripper and/or Pot Holders, Serving/Cutting Spatula, Extra bowl, cooking spray, plastic wrap, and a warm place (for rising dough). For a more detailed recipe with conversions for other pan sizes, &amp; info on other styles of Chicago Pizza, Check out RealDeepDish.com</description>
<source>Edward Heller</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Entree</category>
<category>Pizza</category>
<category>Italian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Chicken Cooked in Foil</title>
<preptime>15 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>40 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 boneless skinless chicken breasts</li>
<li>1⁄2 cup olive oil</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1⁄4 teaspoon pepper</li>
<li>1 teaspoon garlic powder</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Pre-heat oven to 425 degrees F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Rinse chicken and pat dry with paper towel.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cut 4 10&quot; squares of heavy-duty foil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Pour 1 tbsp oil on each sheet of foil- spread to cover foil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place chicken on foil squares.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sprinkle with salt, pepper and garlic powder.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fold and seal foil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place foil packs on cookie sheet.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake for 40 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve chicken from foil packets.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Be careful when opening- steam is trapped inside.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/chicken-cooked-in-foil-26378</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>4</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Serving Size: 1 (147 g)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 4</li>
<li></li>
<li>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 371.1 Calories from Fat 256 69% Total Fat 28.5 g 43% Saturated Fat 4.1 g 20% Cholesterol 68.4 mg 22% Sodium 658.9 mg 27% Total Carbohydrate 0.6 g 0% Dietary Fiber 0.1 g 0% Sugars 0.2 g 0% Protein 27.4 g 54%</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>55mins</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Rhonda Scheurer</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>CHINESE BBQ PORK (Cha Siu)</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime>1 hour</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3 pounds pork shoulder/pork butt</li>
<li>2 tablespoons sugar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>½ teaspoon five spice powder</li>
<li>1 teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>¼ teaspoon white pepper</li>
<li>1 tablespoon sherry or Chinese plum wine</li>
<li>1 tablespoon soy sauce</li>
<li>½ teaspoon sesame oil</li>
<li>2 teaspoons hoisin sauce</li>
<li>2 teaspoons tomato paste</li>
<li>2 teaspoons molasses</li>
<li>1 tablespoon oil</li>
<li>3 cloves minced garlic</li>
<li>1 tablespoon hot water</li>
<li></li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Cut the pork into long strips about 3 inches thick. Combine the rest of the ingredients in a bowl to make the BBQ sauce. Reserve about 2 tablespoons and pour the rest into a large zip top bag along with the pork. Make sure the pork is coated with the sauce, squeeze the air out of the bag, and seal it. Marinate in the refrigerator overnight. Store the reserved sauce for later as well.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In my parent’s restaurant, we had a large standing roasting oven the size of a narrow refrigerator, where the pork could hang from these large S-shaped hooks and roast evenly at very high temperatures. To simulate this at home, preheat your oven to the highest setting (at least 475 degrees). Then line a sheet pan with foil and place a metal rack on top.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Using the metal rack keeps the pork off of the pan and allows it to roast more evenly, like it does in commercial ovens described above. Place the pork on the racks, leaving as much space as possible between pieces, and put the pan in the upper portion of the oven. Pour the rest of the marinade from the bag into a bowl for basting.</li>
<li></li>
<li>After 25 minutes or so, flip the pork and baste with some of the marinating liquid. If needed, add a half cup of water to the bottom of the sheet pan to prevent burning or smoking from the drippings. After another 25-30 minutes, turn on the broiler to crisp the outside and add some color/flavor. Be sure not to walk away during this process, since the sweet BBQ sauce can burn if left unattended.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Take out of the oven and use a clean basting brush to brush the roasted pork with those last couple tablespoons of reserved BBQ sauce. Let the meat rest for 10 minutes and enjoy!</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://thewoksoflife.com/2014/02/chinese-bbq-pork-cha-siu/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/CHINESE_BBQ_PORK_Cha_Siu.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://thewoksoflife.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/DSC_00093.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition>Serves 8</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Ingredients</category>
<category>Asian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime>15 - 18 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 cups + 2 tbsp bleached all-purpose flour (10 2/3 ounces)</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon table salt</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon baking soda</li>
<li>---------------</li>
<li>12 tablespoons unsalted butter (1 1/2 sticks), melted and cooled slightly</li>
<li>1 cup brown sugar (light or dark), 7 ounces</li>
<li>1/2 cup granulated sugar (3 1/2 ounces)</li>
<li>1 large egg</li>
<li>1 large egg yolk</li>
<li>2 teaspoons vanilla extract</li>
<li>-------------------------------------------</li>
<li>Chocolate Chips:</li>
<li>---------------</li>
<li>1 - 2 cups chocolate chips or chunks (semi or bittersweet)</li>
<li>----------------</li>
<li>½ - 1 cups Ghirardelli 66% cacao bittersweet chips.</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Heat oven to 325 degrees. Adjust oven racks to upper- and lower-middle positions. Mix flour, salt, and baking soda together in medium bowl; set aside.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Either by hand or with electric mixer, mix butter and sugars until thoroughly blended. Mix in egg, yolk, and vanilla. Add dry ingredients; mix until just combined. Stir in chips.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Following illustrations below, form scant 1/4 cup dough into ball. Holding dough ball using fingertips of both hands, pull into two equal halves. Rotate halves ninety degrees and, with jagged surfaces exposed, join halves together at their base, again forming a single cookie, being careful not to smooth dough’s uneven surface. Place formed dough onto one of two parchment paper-lined 20-by-14-inch lipless cookie sheets, about nine dough balls per sheet. Smaller cookie sheets can be used, but fewer cookies can be baked at one time and baking time may need to be adjusted. (Dough can be refrigerated up to 2 days or frozen up to 1 month—shaped or not.)</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Bake, reversing cookie sheets’ positions halfway through baking, until cookies are light golden brown and outer edges start to harden yet centers are still soft and puffy, 15 to 18 minutes (start checking at 13 minutes). (Frozen dough requires an extra 1 to 2 minutes baking time.) Cool cookies on cookie sheets. Serve or store in airtight container.</li>
<li></li>
</recipetext>
<url></url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>24</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments><li>SHAPING THICK CHOCOLATE CHIP COOKIES</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. Creating a jagged surface on each dough ball gives the finished cookies an attractive appearance. Start by rolling a scant 1/4 cup of dough into a smooth ball.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Holding the dough ball in the fingertips of both hands, pull the dough apart into two equal halves.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Each half will have a jagged surface where it was ripped from the other. Rotate each piece 90 degrees so that the jagged edge faces up.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Jam the halves back together into one ball so that the top surface remains jagged.</li>
</comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Cook's country - American test kitchen</source>
<video></video>
<category>Cook's Country - American's Test Kitchen</category>
<category>Baking</category>
<category>Snacks</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Cinnamon Rolls</title>
<preptime>1H20M</preptime>
<cooktime>0H30M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>Dough:</li>
<li>1/4 -ounce package yeast</li>
<li>1/2 cup warm water</li>
<li>1/2 cup scalded milk</li>
<li>1/4 cup sugar</li>
<li>1/3 cup butter or shortening</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>3 1/2 to 4 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>Filling:</li>
<li>1/2 cup melted butter, plus more for pan</li>
<li>3/4 cup sugar, plus more for pan</li>
<li>2 tablespoons ground cinnamon</li>
<li>3/4 cup raisins, walnuts, or pecans, optional</li>
<li>Glaze:</li>
<li>4 tablespoons butter</li>
<li>2 cups powdered sugar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</li>
<li>3 to 6 tablespoons hot water</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Heat oven to 350 degrees F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In a small bowl, dissolve yeast in warm water and set aside. In a large bowl mix milk, sugar, melted butter, salt and egg. Add 2 cups of flour and mix until smooth. Add yeast mixture. Mix in remaining flour until dough is easy to handle. Knead dough on lightly floured surface for 5 to 10 minutes. Place in well-greased bowl, cover and let rise until doubled in size, usually 1 to 1 1/2 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>When doubled in size, punch down dough. Roll out on a floured surface into a 15 by 9-inch rectangle. Spread melted butter all over dough. Mix sugar and cinnamon and sprinkle over buttered dough. Sprinkle with walnuts, pecans, or raisins if desired. Beginning at the 15-inch side, role up dough and pinch edge together to seal. Cut into 12 to 15 slices.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Coat the bottom of baking pan with butter and sprinkle with sugar. Place cinnamon roll slices close together in the pan and let rise until dough is doubled, about 45 minutes. Bake for about 30 minutes or until nicely browned.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Meanwhile, mix butter, powdered sugar, and vanilla. Add hot water 1 tablespoon at a time until the glaze reaches desired consistency. Spread over slightly cooled rolls.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Recipe courtesy Paula Deen</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/paula-deen/cinnamon-rolls-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Cinnamon_Rolls.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://foodnetwork.sndimg.com/content/dam/images/food/fullset/2006/6/29/0/pa0711_cin_rolls1.jpg.rend.sni12col.landscape.jpeg</imageurl>
<quantity>12 to 15 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H50M</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Paula Deen</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breakfast</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Classic Brownies</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 1/4 c plain cake flour (5 ounces)</li>
<li>1/2 t table salt</li>
<li>3/4 t baking powder</li>
<li>6 oz unsweetened chocolate , chopped fine</li>
<li>12 tb unsalted butter (1 1/2 sticks), cut into six 1-inch pieces</li>
<li>2 1/4 c sugar (15 3/4 ounces)</li>
<li>4 lg eggs</li>
<li>1 tb vanilla extract</li>
<li>1 c pecans or walnuts (4 ounces), chopped medium (optional)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Adjust oven rack to middle position; heat oven to 325 degrees. Cut</li>
<li>18-inch length foil and fold lengthwise to 8-inch width. Fit foil into</li>
<li>length of 13- by 9-inch baking dish, pushing it into corners and up</li>
<li>sides of pan; allow excess to overhang pan edges. Cut 14-inch length</li>
<li>foil and, if using extra-wide foil, fold lengthwise to 12-inch width;</li>
<li>fit into width of baking pan in same manner, perpendicular to first</li>
<li>sheet. Spray foil-lined pan with nonstick cooking spray.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. If using nuts, spread nuts evenly on rimmed baking sheet and toast</li>
<li>in oven until fragrant, 5 to 8 minutes. Set aside to cool.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Whisk to combine flour, salt, and baking powder in medium bowl; set</li>
<li>aside.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Melt chocolate and butter in large heatproof bowl set over saucepan</li>
<li>of almost-simmering water, stirring occasionally, until smooth.</li>
<li>(Alternatively, in microwave, heat butter and chocolate in large</li>
<li>microwave-safe bowl on high for 45 seconds, then stir and heat for 30</li>
<li>seconds more. Stir again, and, if necessary, repeat in 15-second</li>
<li>increments; do not let chocolate burn.) When chocolate mixture is</li>
<li>completely smooth, remove bowl from saucepan and gradually whisk in</li>
<li>sugar. Add eggs one at time, whisking after each addition until</li>
<li>thoroughly combined. Whisk in vanilla. Add flour mixture in three</li>
<li>additions, folding with rubber spatula until batter is completely</li>
<li>smooth and homogeneous.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5. Transfer batter to prepared pan; using spatula, spread batter into</li>
<li>corners of pan and smooth surface. Sprinkle toasted nuts (if using)</li>
<li>evenly over batter and bake until toothpick or wooden skewer inserted</li>
<li>into center of brownies comes out with few moist crumbs attached, 30</li>
<li>to 35 minutes. Cool on wire rack to room temperature, about 2 hours,</li>
<li>then remove brownies from pan by lifting foil overhang. Cut brownies</li>
<li>into 2-inch squares and serve. (Store leftovers in airtight container</li>
<li>at room temperature up to 3 days.)</li>
</recipetext>
<url>MMF</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Cook's Country - American's Test Kitchen</category>
<category>Baking</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Classic Pork Fried Rice</title>
<preptime>15 minutes</preptime>
<cooktime>10 minutes</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 tablespoon hot water</li>
<li>1 teaspoon honey</li>
<li>1 teaspoon sesame oil</li>
<li>1 teaspoon Shaoxing wine (optional)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon soy sauce</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dark soy sauce</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon white pepper</li>
<li>5 cups cooked Jasmine rice (add 1 teaspoon oil to rice when cooking)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon oil</li>
<li>1 medium onion, diced</li>
<li>1 pound Chinese BBQ pork (cha siu) cut into 1/2 inch chunks (click here for our cha siu recipe!)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>2 eggs, scrambled</li>
<li>1/2 cup bean sprouts</li>
<li>2 scallions, chopped</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Start by combining the hot water, honey, sesame oil, shaoxing wine (if using), soy sauce, dark soy sauce, and white pepper in a small bowl. This is the sauce that you'll be adding to the rice, and it's much easier to have it combined and ready to go before you start cooking.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Take your cooked rice and fluff it with a fork or with your hands (you can rinse your hands in cold water if the rice starts sticking to them). There shouldn't be any big clumps!</li>
<li></li>
<li>With the wok over medium heat, add a tablespoon of oil and sauté the onions until translucent and then stir in the roast pork. Add the rice and mix well. If the rice is cold from the refrigerator, continue stir-frying until the rice is warmed up, which will take about 5 minutes. If the rice was made fresh, then you just need to mix until everything is incorporated.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the sauce mixture and salt and mix with a scooping motion until the rice is evenly coated with sauce. You will have to break up any remaining clumps of rice with the spatula as best as possible, but no need to be obsessive. The rice should be hot by this time.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Toss in your eggs, mung bean sprouts, and scallions. Mix thoroughly for another minute or two and serve!</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://thewoksoflife.com/2014/10/classic-pork-fried-rice/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Classic_Pork_Fried_Rice.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://thewoksoflife.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/pork-fried-rice-recipe-11.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>25 minutes</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Sides</category>
<category>Asian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Crispy Baked Pork Chops</title>
<preptime>25 min</preptime>
<cooktime>35 min</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 bone-in pork rib chops</li>
<li>1 tablespoon plus 2 teaspoons seasoning salt</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1 cup panko bread crumbs</li>
<li>1/2 cup flour</li>
<li>cooking spray</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preheat oven to 400 degrees.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Use about 2 teaspoons of the seasoning salt to season the pork chops.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In one bowl beat 2 eggs. In another bowl combine remaining seasoning salt, panko bread crumbs and flour. Mix well.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dip the pork chops in the eggs. Then dip it in the panko/flour mixture. Then dip once more in the eggs and once more in the flour mixture. Allow to set for 15 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Spray a cooling rack with cooking spray. Place cooling rack on top of a baking sheet. Place prepared pork chops on baking sheet and bake for 25- 35 minutes or until the pork chops are cooked through and crust is crispy. Serve hot.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.lifesambrosia.com/2011/01/crispy-baked-pork-chops-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Crispy_Baked_Pork_Chops.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.lifesambrosia.com/food/crispy-baked-pork-chops.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Serves 4</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description>Inspired by childhood Shake N’ Bake dinners I made my own crispy pork chop breading with seasoning salt, flour and panko.</description>
<source>Deseree Kazda</source>
<video></video>
<category>Entree</category>
<category>Meats</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Easy Baked Chicken</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 pound boneless skinless chicken breasts</li>
<li>Salt and pepper</li>
<li>1 cup Progresso™ chicken broth</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1 Preheat oven to 350° F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2 Place chicken in a baking dish and pour the chicken broth over the chicken.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3 Season with salt and pepper or desired seasonings.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4 Cover with aluminum foil tightly and bake for 30-40 minutes or until chicken has reached the temperature of 165° F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5 Serve with broccoli and mashed potatoes.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.tablespoon.com/recipes/easy-baked-chicken/05e66cb3-cb66-4dbc-acf9-f1e133f877a2</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Easy_Baked_Chicken.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.edge-generalmills.com/c1b10f1b-75bc-4dc4-bc0e-b64a0b02bc1c.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>3</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>0H40M</totaltime>
<description>Chicken baked in chicken broth stays moist and delicious. An easy and healthy dinner.</description>
<source>Girl Who Ate Everything</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Easy Greek Pizza Dough Recipe</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime>20 minutes</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 cups of self-rising flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon of salt</li>
<li>1/4 cup of butter, softened</li>
<li>1 1/4 cups of milk</li>
<li>(olive oil for brushing before cooking)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preparation Combine all dough ingredients. Knead for 20 minutes and set aside until the oven has preheated and toppings are ready. (The dough will start to rise.)</li>
<li>Roll out to a thickness of 1/4 inch, and brush lightly with olive oil before adding toppings.</li>
<li>Yield: makes enough for one 18-inch pizza, two 9-inch pizzas, or three 6-inch pizzas.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://greekfood.about.com/od/greekbreadspitas/r/ladenia_dough.htm</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Easy_Greek_Pizza_Dough_Recipe.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://f.tqn.com/y/greekfood/1/L/Z/a/GettyImages-530022209.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 pizza</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description>Learn to make\ pizza dough - the Greek way. This is an easy recipe for pizza dough that calls for self-rising flour, milk, butter, and salt.</description>
<source>Nancy Gaifyllia</source>
<video></video>
<category>Pizza</category>
<category>Italian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Easy Sandwich Bread - Batter</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 cups (11 ounces) bread flour</li>
<li>6 tablespoons (2 ounces) whole-wheat flour</li>
<li>2 1/4 teaspoons instant or rapid-rise yeast</li>
<li>1 1/4cups plus 2 tablespoons warm water (120 degrees)</li>
<li>3 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted</li>
<li>1 tablespoon honey</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1 large egg, lightly beaten with 1 teaspoon water and pinch salt</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. In bowl of stand mixer, whisk bread flour, whole-wheat flour, and yeast together. Add 1¼ cups warm water, 2 tablespoons melted butter, and honey. Fit stand mixer with paddle and mix on low speed for 1 minute. Increase speed to medium and mix for 2 minutes. Scrape down bowl and paddle with greased rubber spatula. Continue to mix 2 minutes longer. Remove bowl and paddle from mixer. Scrape down bowl and paddle, leaving paddle in batter. Cover with plastic wrap and let batter rise in warm place until doubled in size, about 20 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Adjust oven rack to lower-middle position and heat oven to 375 degrees. Spray 8½ by 4½-inch loaf pan with vegetable oil spray. Dissolve salt in remaining 2 tablespoons warm water. When batter has doubled, attach bowl and paddle to mixer. Add salt-water mixture and mix on low speed until water is mostly incorporated, about 40 seconds. Increase speed to medium and mix until thoroughly combined, about 1 minute, scraping down paddle if necessary. Transfer batter to prepared pan and smooth surface with greased rubber spatula. Cover and leave in warm place until batter reaches ½ inch below edge of pan, 15 to 20 minutes. Uncover and let rise until center of batter is level with edge of pan, 5 to 10 minutes longer.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Gently brush top of risen loaf with egg mixture. Bake until deep golden brown and loaf registers 208 to 210 degrees, 40 to 45 minutes. Using dish towels, carefully invert bread onto wire rack. Reinvert loaf and brush top and sides with remaining 1 tablespoon melted butter. Let cool completely before slicing.</li>
<li></li>
<li></li>
</recipetext>
<url>https://www.americastestkitchen.com/recipes/7671-easy-sandwich-bread</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Easy_Sandwich_Bread.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://d3cizcpymoenau.cloudfront.net/images/19725/detail_SFS_easy_sandwich_bread_CLR-38.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Makes 1 Loaf</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description>The test kitchen’s preferred loaf pan measures 8 1/2 by 4 1/2 inches; if using a 9 by 5-inch pan, check for doneness 5 minutes early. To prevent the loaf from deflating as it rises, do not let the batter come in contact with the plastic wrap. This loaf is best eaten the day it is made, but leftovers may be wrapped in plastic wrap and stored for up to two days at room temperature or frozen for up to one month.</description>
<source></source>
<video>https://www.americastestkitchen.com/recipes/7671-easy-sandwich-bread#</video>
<category>Cook's Country - American's Test Kitchen</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Eggless Pasta</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 cups semolina flour</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1/2 cup warm water</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>In a large bowl, mix flour and salt. Add warm water and stir to make a stiff dough. Increase water if dough seems too dry.</li>
<li>Pat the dough into a ball and turn out onto a lightly floured surface. Knead for 10 to 15 minutes. Cover. Let dough rest for 20 minutes.</li>
<li>Roll out dough using rolling pin or pasta machine. Work with a 1/4 of the dough at one time. Keep the rest covered, to prevent from drying out. Roll by hand to 1/16 of an inch thick. By machine, stop at the third to last setting.</li>
<li>Cut pasta into desired shapes.</li>
<li>Cook fresh noodles in boiling salted water for 3 to 5 minutes. Drain.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/12044/eggless-pasta/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Eggless_Pasta.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/216803.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutrition</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories:</li>
<li></li>
<li>301 kcal</li>
<li></li>
<li>15%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat:</li>
<li></li>
<li>0.9 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>1%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbs:</li>
<li></li>
<li>60.8g</li>
<li></li>
<li>20%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein:</li>
<li></li>
<li>10.6 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>21%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol:</li>
<li></li>
<li>0 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>0%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium:</li>
<li></li>
<li>292 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>12%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Based on a 2,000 calorie diet</li>
<li></li>
<li>See full nutrition</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description>&quot;Anyone on an eggless or low-cholesterol diet will appreciate this recipe.&quot;</description>
<source>Webby</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/3033/eggless-pasta</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Italian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Fake-Fried Chicken</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 pounds boneless skinless chicken thighs (about 8 whole thighs)</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1 tablespoon oregano</li>
<li>3 tablespoons dijon mustard</li>
<li>2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon pepper</li>
<li>splash of milk or buttermilk</li>
<li>splash of hot sauce (optional)</li>
<li>1 cup panko crumbs</li>
<li>Honey or ketchup for serving</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Heat the oven to 425°F. Set a wire rack over a baking sheet.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Remove the thighs from their packaging. If desired, cut into &quot;nugget&quot; bite-sized pieces. Pat dry with a paper towel.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In a small bowl, whisk together the eggs, oregano, dijon, salt, and pepper. Add a splash of milk to loosen it a little. Pour the panko crumbs in another small bowl.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dip each chicken thigh in the egg mixture and gently shake off the extra. Roll the thigh in the panko and set it on the wire rack over the baking sheet. Repeat with remaining chicken thighs.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake for 35-40 minutes for whole thighs or 15-20 minutes for bites. When the thighs are finished, the tops should just be starting to turn golden, juices from the thigh should run clear, and the internal temperature should register at least 165°F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve immediately with bowls of honey and ketchup for dipping.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.thekitchn.com/healthy-recipe-fake-fried-chicken-165374</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Healthy_Dinner_Recipe_FakeFried_Chicken.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://p-fst2.pixstatic.com/506b3bbbfb04d60a51001aa6._w.1500_s.fit_.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Serves 4-6</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Emma Christensen</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Entree</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>French Toast</title>
<preptime>30M</preptime>
<cooktime>30M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>8 slices high-quality white bread</li>
<li>6 tablespoons . unsalted butter</li>
<li>1 1⁄2 cups whole milk</li>
<li>2 large eggs</li>
<li>2 tablespoons sugar</li>
<li>2 teaspoons vanilla extract</li>
<li>3⁄4 teaspoon cinnamon</li>
<li>ground nutmeg, a pinch</li>
<li>1⁄4 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1⁄2 cup all-purpose flour</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Adjust an oven rack to the middle position; preheat oven to 200°.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Arrange the bread on a wire rack set over a baking sheet and bake until slightly dry, about 15 minutes; set aside, leaving the oven on.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Line a second baking sheet with a wire rack; set aside.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Meanwhile, melt 2 tablespoons of the butter and whisk it together with the milk, eggs, sugar, vanilla, cinnamon, nutmeg and salt in a bowl.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Slowly whisk in the flour until smooth.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Pour the batter into a large shallow dish.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Lay 2 pieces of the dried bread in the batter and briefly soak both sides, about 30 seconds per side.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Meanwhile, melt 1 more tablespoon butter in a 12-inch nonstick skillet over medium heat until beginning to brown, swirling to coat the pan.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Remove the bread from the batter, allowing excess batter to drip back into the dish, and lay in the hot skillet.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cook until golden brown on both sides, about 2 1/2 minutes per side.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Transfer the French toast to the wire rack (do not overlap) and keep warm in the oven.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Repeat with the remaining bread, butter, and batter.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/french-toast-americas-test-kitchen-500936</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>1 (106 g)</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 232.9 Calories from Fat 109 47% Total Fat 12.2 g 18% Saturated Fat 6.9 g 34% Cholesterol 74 mg 24% Sodium 239.3 mg 9% Total Carbohydrate 24.4 g 8% Dietary Fiber 0.9 g 3% Sugars 6.7 g 26% Protein 5.8 g 11%</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H</totaltime>
<description>Make and share this French Toast (America's Test Kitchen) recipe from Food.com.</description>
<source>ratherbeswimmin'</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Cook's Country - American's Test Kitchen</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Fresh Pasta Without a Machine</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 c (10 ounces) all-purpose flour</li>
<li>2 lg eggs plus 6 large yolks</li>
<li>2 tb olive oil</li>
<li>1 tb salt</li>
<li>1 recipe sauce (see related recipes)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Process flour, eggs and yolks, and oil in food processor until</li>
<li>mixture forms cohesive dough that feels soft and is</li>
<li></li>
<li>barely tacky to touch, about 45 seconds. (If dough sticks to fingers,</li>
<li>add up to 1/4 cup flour, 1 tablespoon at a</li>
<li></li>
<li>time, until barely tacky. If dough doesn’t become cohesive, add up</li>
<li>to 1 tablespoon water, 1 teaspoon at a time,</li>
<li></li>
<li>until it just comes together; process 30 seconds longer.)</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Turn dough ball onto dry surface and knead until smooth, 1 to 2</li>
<li>minutes. Shape dough into 6-inch-long cylinder. Wrap with plastic wrap</li>
<li>and set aside at room temperature to rest for at least 1 hour and up</li>
<li>to 4 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Cut cylinder crosswise into 6 equal pieces. Working with 1 piece of</li>
<li>dough (rewrap remaining dough), dust both</li>
<li></li>
<li>sides with flour, place cut side down on clean work surface, and press</li>
<li>into 3-inch square. Using heavy rolling pin,</li>
<li></li>
<li>roll into 6-inch square. Dust both sides of dough lightly with flour.</li>
<li>Starting at center of square, roll dough away</li>
<li></li>
<li>from you in 1 motion. Return rolling pin to center of dough and roll</li>
<li>toward you in 1 motion. Repeat steps of rolling until dough sticks to</li>
<li>counter and measures roughly 12 inches long. Lightly dust both sides</li>
<li>of dough with flour and continue rolling dough until it measures</li>
<li>roughly 20 inches long and 6 inches wide, frequently lifting dough to</li>
<li>release it from counter. (You should be able to easily see outline of</li>
<li>your fingers through dough.) If dough firmly sticks to counter and</li>
<li>wrinkles when rolled out, dust dough lightly with flour.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Transfer pasta sheet to kitchen towel and let stand, uncovered,</li>
<li>until firm around edges, about 15 minutes;</li>
<li></li>
<li>meanwhile, roll out remaining dough. Starting with 1 short end, gently</li>
<li>fold pasta sheet at 2-inch intervals until</li>
<li></li>
<li>sheet has been folded into flat, rectangular roll. With sharp chef’s</li>
<li>knife, slice crosswise into 3/16-inch-thick</li>
<li></li>
<li>noodles. Use fingers to unfurl pasta and transfer to baking sheet.</li>
<li>Repeat folding and cutting remaining sheets of</li>
<li></li>
<li>dough. Cook noodles within 1 hour.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5. Bring 4 quarts water to boil in large Dutch oven. Add salt and</li>
<li>pasta and cook until tender but still al dente,</li>
<li></li>
<li>about 3 minutes. Reserve 1 cup pasta cooking water. Drain pasta and</li>
<li>toss with sauce; serve immediately.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Source: America's Test Kitchen</li>
<li></li>
<li>To Make Ahead:</li>
<li></li>
<li>Follow recipe through step 4, transfer baking sheet of pasta to</li>
<li>freezer, and freeze until pasta is</li>
<li></li>
<li>firm. Transfer to zipper-lock bag and store for up to 2 weeks. Cook</li>
<li>frozen pasta straight from freezer as directed in</li>
<li></li>
<li>step 5.</li>
<li></li>
<li>TECHNIQUE</li>
<li></li>
<li>FOOLPROOF APPROACH TO ROLLING AND CUTTING PASTA DOUGH BY HAND</li>
<li></li>
<li>What’s the trick to turning a lump of pasta dough into long, silky</li>
<li>strands—without a pasta roller? Starting with a</li>
<li></li>
<li>soft, malleable dough is half the battle. The other half: dividing the</li>
<li>dough into small, manageable pieces and</li>
<li></li>
<li>working with them one at a time.</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. WORK WITH SMALL PIECES</li>
<li></li>
<li>Shape dough into 6-inch cylinder; wrap in plastic wrap</li>
<li></li>
<li>and let rest for at least 1 hour. Divide into 6 equal</li>
<li></li>
<li>pieces. Reserve 1 piece; rewrap remaining 5.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. START SQUARE</li>
<li></li>
<li>Working with reserved piece, dust both sides with flour,</li>
<li></li>
<li>then press cut side down into 3-inch square. With rolling</li>
<li></li>
<li>pin, roll into 6-inch square, then dust both sides again</li>
<li></li>
<li>with flour.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. ROLL FROM CENTER, ONE WAY AT A TIME</li>
<li></li>
<li>Roll dough to 6 by 12 inches, rolling from center of dough</li>
<li></li>
<li>one way at a time, then dust with flour. Continue rolling</li>
<li></li>
<li>to 6 by 20 inches, lifting frequently to release from</li>
<li></li>
<li>counter. Transfer dough to kitchen towel and air-dry for</li>
<li></li>
<li>about 15 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. FOLD INTO FLAT ROLL</li>
<li></li>
<li>Starting with short end, gently fold dried sheet at 2-inch</li>
<li></li>
<li>intervals to create flat, rectangular roll.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5. CUT INTO STRIPS</li>
<li></li>
<li>With sharp knife, cut into 3/16-inch-thick noodles.</li>
<li></li>
<li>6. UNFURL</li>
<li></li>
<li>Use fingers to unfurl pasta; transfer to baking sheet.</li>
<li></li>
<li>TECHNIQUE</li>
<li></li>
<li>TROUBLESHOOTING FRESH PASTA</li>
<li></li>
<li>This dough is designed to be tacky enough to stick lightly to the</li>
<li>counter, giving it traction to be stretched ultrathin</li>
<li></li>
<li>but not so sticky that it wrinkles when rolled out. Variables such as</li>
<li>flour brand, measuring technique, and size</li>
<li></li>
<li>of the eggs may lead to slight differences in consistency. Here are</li>
<li>tips on how to address texture-related problems</li>
<li></li>
<li>and other issues that may arise.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Problem: Dough isn’t coming together in food processor.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Solution: Add up to 1 tablespoon water, 1 teaspoon at a time, until</li>
<li>dough forms cohesive mass that’s barely tacky</li>
<li></li>
<li>to touch.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Problem: Dough is too sticky.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Solution: Add up to ¼ cup flour, 1 tablespoon at a time, until dough</li>
<li>is barely tacky.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Problem: Dough wrinkles when rolled out.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Solution: Lift dough from counter; dust both sides lightly with flour.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Problem: Dough has too much extra flour, doesn’t stick to counter,</li>
<li>and snaps back when rolled.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Solution: Use pastry brush to dust off excess flour from dough.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Problem: Dough sheet is too dry and cracks when folded.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Solution: Mist sheet lightly with water; let sit few minutes to allow</li>
<li>dough to absorb water before folding again.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Problem: Dough pieces aren’t same size.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Solution: When rolling out, pay more attention to visual cue</li>
<li>provided—dough should be rolled thin enough that</li>
<li></li>
<li>outline of fingers is visible through it—than final dimensions.</li>
<li></li>
<li>BE TRANSPARENT</li>
<li></li>
<li>TECHNIQUE</li>
<li></li>
<li>FORMULA FOR SOFT DOUGH</li>
<li></li>
<li>The biggest hurdle to rolling out dough without a pasta roller is that</li>
<li>it takes muscle to stretch it gossamer thin.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Our solution? Create a super-malleable dough that doesn’t snap back</li>
<li>when you roll it. We did this by adding a</li>
<li></li>
<li>generous splash of olive oil, which coats the flour proteins, limiting</li>
<li>their ability to form gluten so the dough stays</li>
<li></li>
<li>more elastic. We also mixed in six extra egg yolks. Yolks are loaded</li>
<li>with fat and emulsifiers that also limit gluten</li>
<li></li>
<li>development—but because their proteins coagulate when heated, adding</li>
<li>structure, they ensure that the pasta is</li>
<li></li>
<li>strong enough to stay intact when boiled.</li>
<li></li>
<li>LOTS OF OIL AND MORE YOLKS</li>
<li></li>
<li>TECHNIQUE</li>
<li></li>
<li>HOW TO MAKE SHAPED PASTA</li>
<li></li>
<li>Once each piece of pasta has been shaped it should be transferred to</li>
<li>lightly floured rimmed baking sheet. Like the</li>
<li></li>
<li>strand pasta, the shaped pasta should be cooked within an hour of</li>
<li>being shaped or frozen.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Farfalle</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. Cut sheet of dough into 1- by 1½-inch rectangles,</li>
<li></li>
<li>using fluted cutter to cut short side of rectangle.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Place index finger of one hand in center of rectangle.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Using thumb and index finger of other hand, pinch in long</li>
<li></li>
<li>sides of rectangle until they reach finger in center of</li>
<li></li>
<li>pasta. Remove finger and firmly pinch center together.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Garganelli</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. Lay 1½-inch square of pasta diagonally on counter (for</li>
<li></li>
<li>a decorative touch, lay pasta on clean hair comb or wire</li>
<li></li>
<li>rack to create ridges).</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Wrap corner of square around pen or pencil, and with</li>
<li></li>
<li>gentle pressure push away from you until pasta is</li>
<li></li>
<li>completely wrapped around pen. Slide shaped pasta off</li>
<li></li>
<li>pen and repeat.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Maltagliati</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. With short end of pasta sheet facing you, cut pasta at</li>
<li></li>
<li>a 45-degree diagonal into 1-inch strips.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Cut pasta sheet again, perpendicular to first cut, to</li>
<li></li>
<li>create rough diamond-shaped pieces of pasta.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>MMF</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<category>Italian</category>
<category>Entree</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Fresh Semolina and Egg Pasta</title>
<preptime>30M</preptime>
<cooktime>5M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>2 cups semolina flour</li>
<li>1 pinch salt</li>
<li>6 large eggs</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Thoroughly sift together all-purpose flour, semolina flour, and pinch of salt. On a clean surface, make a mountain out of flour mixture then make a deep well in center. Break the eggs into the well and add olive oil. Whisk eggs very gently with a fork, gradually incorporating flour from the sides of the well. When mixture becomes too thick to mix with a fork, begin kneading with your hands.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Knead dough for 8 to 12 minutes, until it is smooth and supple. Dust dough and work surface with semolina as needed to keep dough from becoming sticky. Wrap dough tightly in plastic and allow it to rest at room temperature for 30 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Roll out dough with a pasta machine or a rolling pin to desired thickness. Cut into your favorite style of noodle or stuff with your favorite filling to make ravioli. Bring water to a boil in a large pot, then add 4 teaspoons salt. Cook pasta until tender but not mushy, 1 to 8 minutes depending on thickness. Drain immediately and toss with your favorite sauce.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/fresh-semolina-and-egg-pasta/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Fresh_Semolina_and_Egg_Pasta.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/00/87/51/875171.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fresh Semolina and Egg Pasta</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/8 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 8</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 348</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 71</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 7.8g 12 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 1.7g 9 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 159mg 53 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 102mg 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Potassium 161mg 5 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Carbohydrates 54.5g 18 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dietary Fiber 2.5g 10 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 13.2g 26 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sugars 1.1g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin C 0 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calcium 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Iron 40 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Thiamin 61 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Niacin 55 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin B6 7 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Magnesium 11 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Folate 84 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>* Percent Daily Values are based on a 2,000 calorie diet. Your daily values may be higher or lower depending on your calorie needs.</li>
<li></li>
<li>** Nutrient information is not available for all ingredients. Amount is based on available nutrient data.</li>
<li></li>
<li>(-) Information is not currently available for this nutrient. If you are following a medically restrictive diet, please consult your doctor or registered dietitian before preparing this recipe for personal consumption.</li>
<li></li>
<li>About: Nutrition Info</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H5M</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Just like Mama used to make! Nothing beats fresh pasta, and this simple semolina and egg recipe is the best thing ever. You can use this recipe to make any style of pasta you like, from fettucine to ravioli to lasagna. Semolina is a special variety of wheat flour available at health food stores and gourmet grocery stores.&quot;</description>
<source>jenn</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/3369/fresh-semolina-and-egg-pasta/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Italian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Guinness Lamb Stew with Vegetables</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3 pounds lamb shoulder, well-trimmed and cut into 1-1/2-inch pieces</li>
<li>2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper</li>
<li>3 tablespoons vegetable or olive oil</li>
<li>2 medium yellow onions, cut into 1/2-inch chunks</li>
<li>6 cloves garlic, peeled and smashed</li>
<li>3 tablespoons tomato paste</li>
<li>1/4 cup all-purpose flour</li>
<li>1 cup Guinness</li>
<li>3 cups beef broth</li>
<li>2 cups water, plus 2 tablespoons more for cooking onions and garlic</li>
<li>1 bay leaf</li>
<li>1 small sprig fresh rosemary</li>
<li>2 teaspoons sugar</li>
<li>4 large carrots, peeled and cut into 1-inch chunks on diagonal</li>
<li>1 pound small white boiling potatoes (baby yukons), cut in half</li>
<li>1 cup frozen green peas</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Pat the lamb dry and season with salt and pepper. In a large Dutch oven or heavy pot, heat one tablespoon of oil over medium-high heat until hot and shimmering. Brown the lamb in three batches, adding one more tablespoon of oil for each batch. Do not crowd the pan and let the meat develop a brown crust before turning with tongs. It should take 5-8 minutes per batch. Transfer the browned meat to large bowl and set aside.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the onions, garlic and 2 tablespoons of water to the pot. Cook until the onions are soft, stirring with a wooden spoon to scrape any brown bits from the bottom of pan, about 5 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Stir in the tomato paste and cook a few minutes more.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the lamb with its juices back to the pan and sprinkle with flour. Stir with a wooden spoon until the flour is dissolved, 1-2 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the Guinness, beef broth, water, bay leaf, rosemary sprig and sugar. Stir with a wooden spoon to loosen any brown bits from the bottom of the pan and bring to a boil. Cover the pot with a lid, turn the heat down to low and simmer for one hour and twenty minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the carrots and potatoes to the stew, then cover and continue simmering until the vegetables are cooked and the meat is very tender, 30-40 minutes. (Be sure to stir a few times to prevent vegetables from sticking to bottom.)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Remove the bay leaf and rosemary sprig, and then taste and adjust seasoning if necessary. If serving right away, add the frozen peas and cook until the peas are warmed through. Otherwise, let the stew cool, then cover and store in the refrigerator until ready to serve. Reheat gently on the stovetop and add the peas right before serving.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Note: This stew can be made a day or two ahead of time and reheated gently on the stovetop. Just be sure to add the peas right before serving so they stay fresh. Also, the broth will thicken in the fridge so it may be necessary to thin it with a bit of water (add it little by little).</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.onceuponachef.com/2012/03/guinness-lamb-stew-with-vegetables.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Guinness_Lamb_Stew_with_Vegetables.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.onceuponachef.com/images/2012/03/guinness-lamb-stew-150x150.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4-6</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Per serving (6 servings)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories: 789</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat: 52g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated fat: 20g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbohydrates: 36g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sugar: 9g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fiber: 6g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein: 42g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium: 1242mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol: 150mg</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Jennifer Segal</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Hamburger Buns Recipe</title>
<preptime>25M</preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3/4 to 1 cup lukewarm water</li>
<li>2 tablespoons unsalted butter, cold, cut into pieces</li>
<li>1 large egg</li>
<li>3 1/2 cups King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour</li>
<li>1/4 cup granulated sugar</li>
<li>1 1/4 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1 tablespoon instant yeast</li>
<li>3 tablespoons butter, plus more for the baking sheet</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Mix and knead all of the dough ingredients except for the melted butter by hand, mixer, or bread machine until a soft, smooth dough forms. Cover the dough and let it rise for 1 to 2 hours, or until it’s nearly doubled in bulk.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Gently deflate the dough and divide it into 12 pieces. Shape each piece into a round ball, then flatten it to a squat round blob about 2 1/2 inches across. (Another easy way to shape buns, besides rolling them into balls and flattening, is to gently deflate the dough and form it into a smooth 8-inch log. Using a serrated knife, slice the log into 12 pieces. Gently tug the edges of each piece underneath the ball of dough to form a squat ball.) Place the buns on a lightly buttered or parchment-lined baking sheet, cover, and let rise for about an hour, until noticeably puffy.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Preheat the oven to 375°F (190°C).</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. Brush the buns with about half of the melted butter and bake until golden, 12 to 18 minutes. As soon as you remove the buns from the oven, brush them with the remaining melted butter, which will lend the buns a satiny, buttery crust. Place the buns on a wire rack to cool completely.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://leitesculinaria.com/81501/recipes-hamburger-buns.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Hamburger_Buns_Recipe.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://leitesculinaria.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/hamburger-buns.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Makes 12 beautiful buns</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>01H45M</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Healthy French Fries</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime>1/2 hour</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 lb russet potatoes</li>
<li>1 qt chilled water</li>
<li>1 tray ice cubes</li>
<li>1/2 t salt</li>
<li>spray canola oil</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>After the potatoes are peeled and sliced, place them in a mixing bowl</li>
<li>with cold water and ice cubes. Soak for 30 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat oven to 400°F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>After soaking the potatoes, drain them and then pat dry with a paper</li>
<li>towel.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place the potatoes and salt in a zipper bag. Spray the potatoes for</li>
<li>about three seconds with the canola oil and seal the zipper bag. Shake</li>
<li>to coat the potatoes well with the oil and salt.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carefully place the potatoes on a non-stick cookie sheet. Avoid the</li>
<li>fries touching each other. Spray lightly with the canola oil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place the cookie sheet in the oven and allow the potatoes to bake for</li>
<li>about 7 minutes. Turn the potatoes at least twice, cooking for about 7</li>
<li>minutes after each turn. Total cooking time will be 20 – 25 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve immediately.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Servings = 4 | Serving size =about 4 ounces fries</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cooking Time = 30 Minutes</li>
<li></li>
<li>This recipe can be multiplied by 2.</li>
<li></li>
<li>This recipe can easily be multiplied by 2, but must be cooked in two</li>
<li>batches. These do not keep very well at all.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.drgourmet.com/recipes/extras/frenchfries.shtml#.UztIfvldV9I</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Sides</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Homemade Buttermilk</title>
<preptime>0H15M</preptime>
<cooktime>0H0M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 1/2 teaspoons white vinegar, or fresh lemon juice</li>
<li>1 cup milk</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Place the vinegar in a glass-measuring cup, and add enough milk to make 1 cup total liquid. Stir to combine and let stand for 10 to 15 minutes (The mixture will begin to curdle).</li>
<li></li>
<li>Use as needed in a recipe, or cover and refrigerate until needed.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Recipe courtesy of Emeril Lagasse, 2002</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/emeril-lagasse/homemade-buttermilk-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>1 cup</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>0H15M</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Emeril Lagasse</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Homemade Flour Tortillas</title>
<preptime>15M</preptime>
<cooktime>45M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>2 teaspoons baking powder</li>
<li>2 tablespoons lard</li>
<li>1 1/2 cups water</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Whisk the flour, salt, and baking powder together in a mixing bowl. Mix in the lard with your fingers until the flour resembles cornmeal. Add the water and mix until the dough comes together; place on a lightly floured surface and knead a few minutes until smooth and elastic. Divide the dough into 24 equal pieces and roll each piece into a ball.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat a large skillet over medium-high heat. Use a well-floured rolling pin to roll a dough ball into a thin, round tortilla. Place into the hot skillet, and cook until bubbly and golden; flip and continue cooking until golden on the other side. Place the cooked tortilla in a tortilla warmer; continue rolling and cooking the remaining dough.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/homemade-flour-tortillas/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Homemade_Flour_Tortillas.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/00/66/37/663757.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>2 dozen</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Homemade Flour Tortillas</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/24 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 24</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 86</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 11</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 1.3g 2 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 0.5g 2 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 1mg</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Traditional flour tortillas - homemade and much better than store bought. Do not substitute vegetable oil or shortening for the lard.&quot;</description>
<source>LaDonna</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/3206/homemade-flour-tortillas/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Homemade Hamburger Buns</title>
<preptime>20M</preptime>
<cooktime>15M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 (.25 ounce) package active dry yeast (such as Fleischmann's ActiveDry Yeast®)</li>
<li>1 pound all-purpose flour, or as needed - divided</li>
<li>1 cup warm water (105 degrees F/41 degrees C)</li>
<li>1 large egg</li>
<li>3 tablespoons butter, melted</li>
<li>3 tablespoons white sugar</li>
<li>1 1/4 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon olive oil</li>
<li>1 egg, beaten</li>
<li>1 tablespoon milk</li>
<li>1 teaspoon sesame seeds, or as needed</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Line a baking sheet with a silicone mat or parchment paper.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place yeast into bowl of a large stand mixer; whisk in 1/2 cup flour and warm water until smooth. Let stand until mixture is foamy, 10 to 15 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Whisk 1 egg, melted butter, sugar, and salt thoroughly into yeast mixture. Add remaining flour (about 3 cups).</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fit a dough hook onto stand mixer and knead the dough on low speed until soft and sticky, 5 to 6 minutes. Scrape sides if needed. Poke and prod the dough with a silicone spatula; if large amounts of dough stick to the spatula, add a little more flour.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Transfer dough onto a floured work surface; dough will be sticky and elastic but not stick to your fingers. Form the dough lightly into a smooth, round shape, gently tucking loose ends underneath.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Wipe out stand mixer bowl, drizzle olive oil into the bowl, and turn dough over in the bowl several times to coat surface thinly with oil. Cover bowl with aluminum foil. Let dough rise in a warm place until doubled, about 2 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Transfer dough to a floured work surface and pat to flatten bubbles and form into a slightly rounded rectangle of dough about 5x10 inches and about 1/2 inch thick. Dust dough lightly with flour if needed. Cut dough into 8 equal pieces. Form each piece into a round shape, gently tucking ends underneath as before.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Use your hands to gently pat and stretch the dough rounds into flat disc shapes about 1/2 inch thick. Arrange buns about 1/2 inch apart on prepared baking sheet. Dust buns very lightly with flour. Drape a piece of plastic wrap over the baking sheet (do not seal tightly). Let buns rise until doubled, about 1 hour.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat oven to 375 degrees F (190 degrees C).</li>
<li></li>
<li>Beat 1 egg with milk in a small bowl, using a fork, until mixture is thoroughly combined. Very gently and lightly brush tops of buns with egg wash without deflating the risen dough. Sprinkle each bun with sesame seeds.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake in the preheated oven until lightly browned on top, 15 to 17 minutes. Buns will stick together slightly where they touch. Let cool completely, tear the buns apart, and slice in half crosswise to serve.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/homemade-hamburger-buns/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Homemade_Hamburger_Buns.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/01/89/12/1891296.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 buns</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Homemade Hamburger Buns</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/8 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 8</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 292</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 63</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 7g 11 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 3.3g 17 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 64mg 21 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 415mg 17 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Potassium 101mg 3 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Carbohydrates 48.6g 16 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dietary Fiber 1.8g 7 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 7.9g 16 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sugars 5g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin C</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>3H45M</totaltime>
<description>&quot;I've gotten a thousand request for these. We're going to make our own, and not only are these going to be the perfect shape, they're going to taste way better than anything that comes out of a plastic bag. The total time takes almost 4 hours, but the actual amount of work involved is maybe 10 minutes.&quot;</description>
<source>Chef John</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/3772/homemade-hamburger-buns/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Homemade Nacho Cheese Powder</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3/4 cup cheddar cheese powder</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon garlic powder</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon chili powder</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoons sugar</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoons salt</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Pulse everything together in a spice grinder until you have a smooth powder.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sprinkle on popcorn, pretzels, tacos, sloppy joes, or whatever appeals to you.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.cupcakeproject.com/2014/01/homemade-nacho-cheese-powder.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Homemade_Nacho_Cheese_Powder.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.cupcakeproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Nacho-Cheese-Powder-01.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>Just over 3/4 cup nacho cheese powder</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Homemade Vanilla Extract</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3 to 5 vanilla beans</li>
<li>8 ounces alcohol such as vodka, bourbon, brandy, or rum</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Split the vanilla beans: Split each vanilla bean in half lengthwise. If you like, you can leave an inch connected at the end of the bean for an attractive presentation. You can also chop the beans into smaller pieces if necessary to fit in your jar or bottle.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place the vanilla beans in a jar and cover with alcohol: Place the vanilla beans in a clean jar or bottle. Cover them with alcohol, making sure they are completely submerged. Cover the jar or bottle and give it a good shake.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Infuse for at least one month: Store the jar or bottle of vanilla beans in a cool, dark place for at least one month, shaking it from time to time. Taste the extract and let it infuse longer if you want a stronger flavor.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Strain it if you like: You may wish to remove the vanilla pods and decant the extract into a pretty bottle. The little flecks of seeds can be a nice touch, but if you want a clear extract you can strain them out using a coffee filter.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Or leave the pods in the extract: You can also leave the beans in the alcohol and top off the bottle as you use the extract. Eventually all the flavor will be extracted from the original vanilla beans, so you can periodically add fresh beans as well as leftover pods that you've scraped for other recipes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>→ Uses for spent pods. You can also make good use of the spent vanilla pods by drying them and then making vanilla sugar or flavored salt.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-homemade-vanilla-extract-cooking-lessons-from-the-kitchn-197785</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Homemade_Vanilla_Extract.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://p-fst1.pixstatic.com/529e62c9697ab0771a0023a9._w.1500_s.fit_.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>General Rule of Thumb: Use 3 to 5 vanilla beans per 8 ounces of alcohol and multiply accordingly if making more extract.</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Emily Han</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Homestyle Potato Chips</title>
<preptime>40M</preptime>
<cooktime>20M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 medium potatoes, peeled and sliced paper-thin</li>
<li>3 tablespoons salt</li>
<li>1 quart oil for deep frying</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Place potato slices into a large bowl of cold water as you slice. Drain, and rinse, then refill the bowl with water, and add the salt. Let the potatoes soak in the salty water for at least 30 minutes. Drain, then rinse and drain again.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Heat oil in a deep-fryer to 365 degrees F (185 degrees C). Fry potato slices in small batches. Once they start turning golden, remove and drain on paper towels. Continue until all of the slices are fried. Season with additional salt if desired.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/homestyle-potato-chips/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Homestyle_Potato_Chips.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/00/16/47/164745.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Homestyle Potato Chips</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/8 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 8</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 179</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 100</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 11.1g 17 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 1.4g 7 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 0mg 0 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 2623mg 105 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Potassium 449mg 13 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Carbohydrates 18.6g 6 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dietary Fiber 2.3g 9 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 2.2g 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>** Sugars 0.8g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Making homestyle potato chips is fun and easy. Guaranteed they won't last long! A food processor with a slicing attachment is very helpful. Experiment with the thickness; you may like them thicker or thinner. I like to use olive oil because it has less trans fats, but you can use safflower, corn, or peanut oil as well as vegetable oil.&quot;</description>
<source>ALMALOU</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/3334/homestyle-potato-chips/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Snacks</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>light brioche hamburger buns</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 c. warm water</li>
<li>3 tablespoons warm milk</li>
<li>2 teaspoons active dry yeast</li>
<li>2½ tablespoons sugar</li>
<li>2 large eggs</li>
<li>3 cups bread flour</li>
<li>⅓ cup all-purpose flour</li>
<li>1½ teaspoons salt</li>
<li>2½ tablespoons unsalted butter, softened.</li>
<li>sesame seeds (optional)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>In a glass measuring cup, combine 1 cup warm water, 3 tbsp. milk, yeast and sugar. Let stand until foamy, about 5 minutes. Meanwhile, beat 1 egg.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In the bowl of a stand mixer, add the flours, salt and butter. Using the paddle attachment, mix the ingredients until the butter is the size of crumbs.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Stir in yeast mixture and beaten egg. Run the mixer on medium-low (I used #3 on my Kitchen Aid) until a dough forms, about 8-10 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Shape the dough into a ball and return it to the bowl (it will be sticky and wet). Cover bowl with a clean, damp kitchen towel and let the dough rise in a warm place until it has doubled is size, 1- 3 hours* See Note.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Line a baking sheet with parchment paper. Using a dough scraper (or chef's knife), divide the dough into 8 equal parts. If you have a scale, weigh each piece to guarantee that they're all the same size.</li>
<li></li>
<li>To shape the dough into balls, gently flatten each piece like a pancake. Pull up each side pinching it together in the center. Repeat until the ball is sealed. Flip the ball over (seam side down) and move to an un-floured part of your board (it's easier to roll this way). Place your palm over the top and gently roll into a smooth ball. Transfer to a parchment lined baking sheet, placing them 2 to 3 inches apart. Cover loosely with plastic wrap and let buns rise in a warm place for 1-2 hours, or until puffy and slightly risen.</li>
<li></li>
<li>To make the egg wash, beat the remaining egg with a splash of water. When the buns are finished with the 2nd rise, gently brush each one with egg wash. At this point, you could add sesame seeds to the top of your rolls if desired.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat your oven to 400 F. and place a shallow baking pan on the oven floor. Before the dough goes in, add about ½ cup of water to the pan (to create steam). This will help keep the bread nice and moist. Bake for about 15-20 minutes or until golden brown. Transfer to a wire rack to cool completely.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.theclevercarrot.com/2013/05/light-brioche-hamburger-buns/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/light_brioche_hamburger_buns.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.theclevercarrot.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/IMG_03691.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 buns</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Revati</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breads</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Marinated Baked Pork Chops</title>
<preptime>15 m</preptime>
<cooktime>1 h</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 tablespoon soy sauce</li>
<li>2 tablespoons vegetable oil</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
<li>2 tablespoons brown sugar</li>
<li>2 tablespoons ketchup</li>
<li>6 pork chops, trimmed</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C).</li>
<li></li>
<li>In a small bowl, thoroughly blend soy sauce, vegetable oil, Worcestershire sauce, lemon juice, brown sugar, and ketchup.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place pork chops in a medium baking dish, and spread with 1/2 the sauce.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake pork chops 30 minutes in the preheated oven. Turn, and spread with remaining sauce. Continue baking 30 minutes, or until internal temperature of the chops has reached 145 degrees F (63 degrees C).</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/44742/marinated-baked-pork-chops/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Marinated_Baked_Pork_Chops.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/720x405/820973.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>6</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutrition</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories:</li>
<li></li>
<li>166 kcal</li>
<li></li>
<li>8%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat:</li>
<li></li>
<li>8.8 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>14%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbs:</li>
<li></li>
<li>6.5g</li>
<li></li>
<li>2%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein:</li>
<li></li>
<li>14.6 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>29%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol:</li>
<li></li>
<li>36 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>12%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium:</li>
<li></li>
<li>256 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>10%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Based on a 2,000 calorie diet</li>
<li></li>
<li>See full nutrition</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1 h 15 m</totaltime>
<description>&quot;My family loves this recipe. It is quick and easy, and makes for a tasty weekday supper. I often double the sauce to serve over rice.&quot;</description>
<source>Kim</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/2695/marinated-baked-pork-chops</video>
<lang>en</lang>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Microwave Potato Chips</title>
<preptime>0H15M</preptime>
<cooktime>0H10M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 large Yukon Gold potatoes (about 1 pound)</li>
<li>3 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>Kosher salt</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Special equipment: a mandolin</li>
<li>Thinly slice the potatoes about 1/16-inch thick using a mandolin. Put the potato slices in a large bowl of cold water and stir to release the starch. Drain and refill the water as many times as necessary until the water remains clear. Line a baking sheet with paper towels. Transfer the potatoes to the paper towels and pat dry.</li>
<li>Line a large microwave-safe plate (the biggest that will fit in your microwave) with two layers of paper towel. Arrange as many potato slices on the paper towels as will fit in one layer without touching. Lightly brush the potatoes on both sides with oil and sprinkle lightly with salt. Microwave at full power for 3 minutes. Flip the slices over and microwave at 60-percent power until crispy and golden brown in spots, about 2 minutes more. Transfer the chips to a serving bowl and repeat with the remaining potatoes.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/microwave-potato-chips0.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Microwave_Potato_Chips.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://foodnetwork.sndimg.com/content/dam/images/food/fullset/2016/6/10/1/VB0303H_Microwave-Potato-Chips_s4x3.jpg.rend.sni12col.landscape.jpeg</imageurl>
<quantity>4 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>0H25M</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Recipe courtesy of Valerie's Home Cooking</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Snacks</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Neapolitan Pizza</title>
<preptime>
			6 hours
		</preptime>
<cooktime>
			7 minutes
		</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>Dough</li>
<li></li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon active dry yeast</li>
<li>1 1/4 cups warm water 100-110 degrees</li>
<li>4 cups unbleached “00” flour</li>
<li>2 teaspoons fine sea salt</li>
<li>2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil plus more for bowl</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sauce</li>
<li></li>
<li>28 oz whole San Marzano tomatoes, passed with juices through a food mill</li>
<li></li>
<li>Topping</li>
<li></li>
<li>12 ounces Mozzarella di Bufala (see note) or mozzarella fior di latte cheese, cut into 1/4-inch-thick slices</li>
<li>4 large or 8 small basil leaves</li>
<li>Extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>Medium coarse sea salt</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1.   Make the dough: Sprinkle yeast over water; let stand until yeast is creamy, 5 to 10 minutes. (If yeast does not</li>
<li>become creamy, discard and start over with new yeast.)</li>
<li></li>
<li>2.   In a large bowl, whisk together flour and salt; form a well in center. Add yeast mixture and oil; stir until dough</li>
<li>just comes together. Turn out dough onto a lightly floured work surface and knead vigorously, for 10 minutes. Cover with a damp dishtowel and let rest for 10 minutes, then knead vigorously for 10 minutes</li>
<li>more. Lightly oil a large bowl. Form dough into a ball, transfer to bowl and turn to lightly coat with oil.</li>
<li>Cover bowl tightly with plastic wrap and refrigerate overnight.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3.  Punch down dough with your fist (dough will be stiff), then fold sides over one another, turn dough, tightly</li>
<li>cover bowl with plastic wrap and refrigerate at least 4 hours or up to 24 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4.  Divide dough into 4 pieces; shape pieces into balls and place on a lightly floured work surface, leaving a few</li>
<li>inches between balls. Loosely cover with a damp dishtowel (not terry cloth) and let rise at warm room temperature until doubled, about 2 hours; time may vary depending on room temperature and freshness of</li>
<li>yeast. If skin forms on dough while rising, lightly spray surface with water.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5.  Heat Stone While Dough Rises: Position rack in lower third of oven. Place pizza stone on rack. At least 45</li>
<li>minutes before baking pizza, heat oven to maximum temperature (500 to 550 degrees).</li>
<li></li>
<li>6.  Assemble Pizza: On a lightly floured work surface, press 1 dough ball with your fingers to begin to shape   into</li>
<li>a round. Use your fist and hands to gently stretch dough to a 10-inch round. (A floured rolling pin can used</li>
<li>be to help roll out dough.) Transfer dough to a lightly floured peel; gently shake peel to make sure dough</li>
<li>does not stick.</li>
<li></li>
<li>7.  Working fairly quickly, spread a 1/3 cup sauce over dough, leaving about a 1/2 -inch border. Tear 3 ounces</li>
<li>cheese into pieces and arrange on top of sauce. Tear 1 or 2 basil leaves into small pieces and arrange on top.</li>
<li>Drizzle very lightly with oil and sprinkle with salt. Slide pizza onto stone. Bake until cheese is melted and</li>
<li>bubbling in spots and edge of dough is crisp and golden, about 7 minutes. Using the peel and a large spatula</li>
<li>or pair of tongs, transfer pizza to a plate and serve.  Repeat with remaining ingredients.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>
			http://www.theartfulgourmet.com/2013/08/11/neapolitan-pizza-making-with-the-pros/
		</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>
			3
		</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments><li>Soft “00” flour produces a pliable, easy-to-work-with pizza dough and a tender yet sturdy crust with a crisp yet not too dry edge. Mozzarella fior di latte has a firmer texture than Mozzarella di Bufala, which falls apart when cut, though both cheeses are creamy when melted. You can find “00” flour, San Marzano tomatoes, mozzarella di bufala, mozzarella fior di latte at Italian markets, specialty stores, and online.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Recipe by La Cucina Italiana Magazine</li>
</comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Pizza</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>New England Greek Style Pizza Recipe</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>For the Dough</li>
<li>400 grams (14 ounces, about 2 1/2 cups) bread flour</li>
<li>4 grams (about 1/2 teaspoon) instant yeast</li>
<li>8 grams (about 1 tablespoon) kosher salt (or 1 1/2 teaspoons table salt)</li>
<li>2 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>260 grams (about 1 cup plus 2 tablespoons) water</li>
<li>&amp;nbsp</li>
<li>For the Sauce</li>
<li>2 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>2 medium cloves garlic, grated on a microplane grater (about 2 teaspoons)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried oregano</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon red pepper flakes</li>
<li>3 ounces tomato paste</li>
<li>1 (28-ounce) can crushed tomatoes</li>
<li>Kosher salt</li>
<li>To assemble</li>
<li>2 tablespoons vegetable shortening, melted</li>
<li>2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil</li>
<li>8 ounces freshly grated whole milk mozzarella</li>
<li>8 ounces freshly grated white cheddar</li>
<li>2 ounces Parmigiano-Reggiano</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Combine flour, yeast, and salt in a large bowl and whisk until homogenous. Add oil and water and stir with wooden spoon until combined. Cover with plastic wrap and let rise at room temperature at least 8 hours and up to 24.</li>
<li>The next day, turn dough out onto lightly floured surface and dived in half. Form balls with each half, then place into lightly oiled bowls, coating all surfaces of the balls with oil. Cover with plastic wrap and set aside at room temperature.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, make the sauce. Heat olive oil in a medium saucepan over medium-high heat until shimmering. Add garlic, oregano, and pepper flakes and cook for thirty seconds until fragrant. Add tomato paste and cook, stirring constantly for 1 minute. Add two thirds of crushed tomatoes and stir to combine. Reduce heat to lowest setting and cook, stirring occasionally for 1 hour. Stir in remaining tomato sauce and season to taste with salt. Remove from heat and set aside.</li>
<li>Stretch the dough: Coat two 10-inch cast iron skillet (or cake pans/oven-safe nonstick pans) with 1 tablespoon each of shortening and olive oil. Transfer dough balls one at a time to a large cookie sheet and stretch out into a 10-inch circle. Transfer the circle to the greased skillet. Cover and allow to rise for 1 hour at room temperature. Meanwhile, adjust the oven rack to the bottom position and preheat oven to 500°F. Combine the cheeses in a large bowl and cover until ready to use.</li>
<li>When dough has risen, top each circle with 1 cup of sauce (you will have leftover sauce), spreading it to within half an inch of the edge. Divide grated cheese evenly between the two pies, spreading it all the way to the edge of each pie.</li>
<li>Bake pies until top is bubbly and golden brown in spots and cheese has charred around edges, 15 to 20 minutes. Remove pizzas from oven and using a thin metal spatula, release the edges from the pans. Carefully lift pies to check for doneness underneath. If you'd like a darker bottom crust, set each pie directly over a medium-low flame and cook, turning occasionally until desired level of doneness is reached.</li>
<li>Slide pizza onto cutting board, allow to rest two minutes, slice, and serve.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2011/08/new-england-greek-style-pizza.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/New_England_Greek_Style_Pizza_Recipe.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/assets_c/2011/08/20110818-pizza-lab-greek-primary-1-thumb-625xauto-181332.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4 to 6 (two 10-inch pizzas)</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description><li>This recipe appears in: The Pizza Lab: How To Make New England Greek-style Pizza At Home</li>
<li></li>
<li>Note: You don't have to use a cast iron pan for this - dedicated pizza pans, cake pans that you don't mind ruining, or a nonstick skillet will work just fine. You'll end up with more sauce than you need, which can be stored int he fridge for up to a week. Eat it with pasta, or more pizza! For best results, do not use pregrated cheese. It won't brown or melt properly.</li>
</description>
<source>J. Kenji López-Alt</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Pizza</category>
<category>Italian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>One Ingredient Cheddar Cheese Crackers</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient>six ounces shredded cheddar cheese</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Spread the cheddar cheese on a cookie sheet fitted with a Silpat or parchment paper. Try to not have too much overlap (like a hill of cheese), but a little is OK.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Set your oven to 170 F and leave the cheese in the oven overnight (about eight hours).</li>
<li></li>
<li>When you open your oven, you’ll see that the cheese has hardened and joined together into one giant cheese cracker.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Wipe off any excess grease from both sides, break into cracker-sized pieces, and enjoy!</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.cupcakeproject.com/2014/01/one-ingredient-cheddar-cheese-crackers.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/One_Ingredient_Cheddar_Cheese_Crackers.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.cupcakeproject.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Cheddar-Crackers-Titled.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 cookie sheet worth of cheddar cheese crackers</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Snacks</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Oven-Smoked Bacon</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>5 tablespoons Diamond Crystal kosher salt</li>
<li>2 tablespoons granulated sugar</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon curing salt</li>
<li>1 (5- to 5-1/2-pound) slab fresh, skin-on pork belly (1/2 of a whole belly slab)</li>
<li>2 (18-inch-by-4-1/2-feet) sheets heavy-duty aluminum foil</li>
<li>5 cups apple wood or hickory smoking chips</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>For the cure:</li>
<li></li>
<li>1Combine the kosher salt, sugar, and curing salt in a small bowl.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2Trim off any uneven edges on the pork belly. Place the belly skin-side down on a work surface. Sprinkle it evenly with half of the curing mixture and rub the mixture into the meat until it’s absorbed. Flip the belly over and sprinkle it evenly with the remaining curing mixture. Let it sit until the curing mixture is absorbed and moisture has beaded on top, about 5 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3Place the belly in an extra-large (2- to 2-1/2-gallon) resealable plastic bag. (Alternatively, you can place it in a roasting pan and cover it tightly with aluminum foil.) Refrigerate for 7 days, flipping the belly every other day.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4When the belly is ready, fit a wire rack over a baking sheet. Remove the belly from the bag, rinse it under cool water, and pat it very dry with paper towels. Place it on the rack skin-side up and refrigerate uncovered overnight.</li>
<li></li>
<li>For the smoking:</li>
<li></li>
<li>1Let the pork belly sit at room temperature for 1 hour. Meanwhile, remove all of the racks from the oven except one arranged in the lowest position. Heat the oven to 200°F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2Line the inside of a roasting pan crosswise with the foil, overlapping it in the center of the pan by about 1 inch. Make sure that the bottom and sides of the pan are completely covered and that the excess foil extends over the long sides and slightly up and over the short sides of the pan.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3Scatter the wood chips in an even layer over the foil in the bottom of the pan. Fit a roasting rack over the chips. (The roasting rack should sit at least 1 1/2 inches above the bottom of the pan. You can try flipping it over if needed. If your roasting rack still sits too low, use a wire steaming or cooling rack that sits at least 1 1/2 inches above the bottom of the pan.) Place the belly on the rack skin-side up. Bring the long edges of the foil up to meet in the middle. Fold the foil down twice and crimp it to close tightly, making sure it is not touching the belly so that the smoke can circulate around it. Bring up the foil on the sides to meet the top seam and crimp, making sure the entire rack and belly are completely surrounded with foil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4Place the roasting pan across two burners over medium-high heat until a steady stream of smoke pours out of the top seam of the foil bundle, about 5 minutes. (This step doesn’t produce a ton of smoke, but you still may want to open a window or turn on the fan above your range.)</li>
<li></li>
<li>5Place the pan in the oven and smoke until the pork belly reaches 150°F on an instant-read thermometer, about 4 to 6 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>6Remove the pan to a wire rack. Carefully open the top seam of the foil and let the bacon cool to room temperature. Cut off and discard the skin. Wrap the bacon tightly in plastic wrap and refrigerate it overnight before slicing and cooking. It can be kept tightly wrapped for up to 2 weeks in the refrigerator or up to 3 months in the freezer, but before freezing, be sure to wrap the bacon in plastic wrap and then foil to prevent freezer burn.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Share This Recipe</li>
<li></li>
<li>Print</li>
<li></li>
<li>Email</li>
<li></li>
<li>Save (126)</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.chowhound.com/recipes/oven-smoked-bacon-30156</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/OvenSmoked_Bacon.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://search.chow.com/thumbnail/320/0/www.chowstatic.com/assets/recipe_photos/30156_oven_smoked_bacon.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>About 4 1/2 pounds</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>30 mins, plus 9 days curing, smoking, and chilling time</totaltime>
<description><li>Making smoked bacon at home seems impossible if you don’t have a smoker and an outdoor space, but after many trials, the CHOW test kitchen has come up with this method that works in your kitchen oven. All you need is a roasting pan, a roasting rack, aluminum foil, and wood chips. We like the deep, smoky flavor that traditional hickory chips add to the bacon, but apple wood is also good if you want a lighter, sweeter option. Try this flavorful, smoky bacon in our Bacon-Maple Sticky Buns, a Triple-Pork Club Sandwich, or a fancy pasta dish.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Special equipment: You will need a roasting pan fitted with a roasting rack that sits at least 1 1/2 inches above the bottom of the pan. You can try flipping the roasting rack over (like we did) if it sits too close to the bottom in its traditional orientation. Or use a wire cooling or steaming rack.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Giant resealable storage bags, like these jumbo 2-gallon bags, were the perfect size to use for the curing process. If you can’t find these bags, you can cure the bacon in a roasting pan covered with foil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>To smoke the bacon, you will need at least 3 yards of 18-inch-wide heavy-duty aluminum foil.</li>
<li></li>
<li>What to buy: Pork belly is the same as fresh bacon. You can order it from a reputable butcher. A whole fresh pork belly with the skin on weighs around 11 pounds, of which you’ll need half (a 5-1/2-pound slab).</li>
<li></li>
<li>Curing salt, also known as pink salt or saltpeter, contains 6.25 percent sodium nitrite. It is colored pink so as not to be confused with regular salt. Curing salt is available at Butcher &amp; Packer.</li>
<li></li>
<li>It’s especially important to use kosher salt here to ensure that your quantity is correct. We prefer the Diamond Crystal brand, available in most grocery stores. If you use Morton kosher salt, you will need 1/4 cup. If you have another brand, weigh out 43 grams.</li>
<li></li>
<li>You should buy pure, resin-free, bark-free wood chips. For this recipe, we recommend apple wood or hickory chips, which can be purchased at most hardware stores and grocery stores during the summer months, or online.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Game plan: The entire curing, smoking, and chilling process takes at least 9 days, so plan accordingly.</li>
<li></li>
<li>This recipe was featured as part of our How to Make Oven-Smoked Bacon project.</li>
</description>
<source>Christine Gallary</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Pancakes</title>
<preptime>10M</preptime>
<cooktime>10M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>6 tbsp milk</li>
<li>1 tbsp white vinegar</li>
<li>½ cup all purpose flour</li>
<li>1 tbsp white sugar</li>
<li>½ tsp baking powder</li>
<li>¼ tsp baking soda</li>
<li>¼ tsp salt</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>1 tbsp butter, melted</li>
<li>cooking spray</li>
<li></li>
<li>---------------------------------</li>
<li>½ tsp cinnamon</li>
<li>⅛ tsp (Dash) Vanilla extract</li>
<li>---------------------------------</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Combine milk with vinegar in a medium bowl and set aside for 5 minutes to &quot;sour&quot;.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Combine flour, sugar, baking powder, baking soda, and salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk egg and butter into &quot;soured&quot; milk. Pour the flour mixture into the wet ingredients and whisk until lumps are gone.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Heat a large skillet over medium heat, and coat with cooking spray. Pour 1/4 cupfuls of batter onto the skillet, and cook until bubbles appear on the surface. Flip with a spatula, and cook until browned on the other side.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/fluffy-pancakes-2/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Fluffy_Pancakes.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/00/84/23/842371.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4 pancakes</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fluffy Pancakes</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/4 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 4</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 230</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 74</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 8.2g 13 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 4.7g 23 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 72mg 24 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 650mg 26 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>** Potassium 121mg 3 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Carbohydrates 32.7g 11 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dietary Fiber 0.8g 3 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 6.4g 13 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sugars 8.6g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A 6 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin C</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>25M</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Tall and fluffy. These pancakes are just right. Topped with strawberries and whipped cream, they are impossible to resist.&quot;</description>
<source>kris</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/888/fluffy-pancakes/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breakfast</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Peanut Butter Pretzel Pie Recipe</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>5 ounces thin pretzel twists</li>
<li>2 ounces butter, melted and cooled</li>
<li>3 quarts vanilla ice cream, softened (a brand that is airy, such as Bryers or Friendly's works best)</li>
<li>6 ounces smooth peanut butter, divided into 5 ounces and 1 ounce, melted until it turns to liquid</li>
<li>2 ounces cold heavy cream, whipped</li>
<li>Optional toppings: crushed peanut butter cups, butterfingers, pretzels, or salted peanuts</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1.</li>
<li>In the bowl of a food processor, pulverize the pretzels until they are like gravel; some bigger pieces, some smaller pieces, and some sandy-textured crumbs. Add the melted butter and stir to combine. Pour the mixture into the pie plate and press it evenly against the bottom and sides to form the crust. Freeze for 10 minutes.</li>
<li>2.</li>
<li>In a bowl using a large spatula, stir the ice cream until it is pliable but still frozen; the consistency of soft serve. Drizzle 5 ounces of the peanut butter over it, and fold it into the ice cream. Pour the frozen mixture into the prepared shell and smooth the top so it is sightly domed. Draw a divot in the top of the dome and pour the remaining peanut butter into it. Freeze the pie for 4 hours to set.</li>
<li>3.</li>
<li>When ready to serve, pipe cold whipped cream around the perimeter of the pie. Sprinkle the chopped topping of your choice over the top. Serve immediately.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2012/07/peanut-butter-pretzel-pie-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Peanut_Butter_Pretzel_Pie_Recipe.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/assets_c/2012/07/20120713-195206-peanutbutter-pretzel-pie-610x458-1-thumb-625xauto-259029.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>serves 8</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description><li>This recipe appears in: Pie of the Week: Peanut Butter Pretzel Ice Cream Pie</li>
<li></li>
<li>[Photograph: Lauren Weisenthal]</li>
<li></li>
<li>When you can't stand the heat of summer, cool off with this no-bake pie. There's nothing like the combination of salty and sweet, and this pie brings the two together in perfect harmony by combining creamy sweet vanilla ice cream with peanut butter and a pretzel crumb crust.</li>
<li></li>
<li>About the author: Lauren Weisenthal has logged many hours working in restaurant kitchens and bakeries of Brooklyn and Manhattan. She is a graduate of the Artisan Bread Baking and Pastry Arts programs at the French Culinary Institute. You can follow her on Twitter at @evillagekitchen.</li>
</description>
<source>Lauren Weisenthal</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Dessert</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Perfect Prime Rib</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 standing rib roast (prime rib), 3-12 pounds (see note above)</li>
<li>Kosher salt</li>
<li>Freshly ground black pepper</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat oven to lowest possible temperature setting, 150°F or greater (some ovens can't hold a temperature below 200°F). Season roast generously with kosher salt and fresh ground black pepper. Place roast, with fat cap up, on v-rack set in large roasting pan. Place in oven and cook until center of roast registers 120°F on an instant-read thermometer for medium-rare, or 135°F for medium. In a 150°F oven, this will take around 5 1/2 to 6 1/2 hours. In a 200°F oven, this will take 3 1/2 to 4 hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Remove roast from oven and tent loosely with aluminum foil. Place in a warm spot in the kitchen and allow to rest for at least 30 minutes, and up to an hour and a half. Meanwhile, preheat oven to highest possible temperature setting (500°F to 550°F)</li>
<li></li>
<li>3.</li>
<li></li>
<li>10 minutes before guests are ready to be served, remove foil, and place roast back in hot oven and cook until well-browned and crisp on the exterior, 6-10 minutes. Remove from oven, carve, and serve immediately.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2009/12/perfect-prime-rib-beef-recipe.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Perfect_Prime_Rib.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/assets_c/2011/12/20091218-rib-roast-perfect-thumb-625xauto-204235.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>3 to 12, depending on size of roast</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description><li>This recipe appears in: The Food Lab's Definitive Guide to Prime Rib Serious Entertaining: A Blowout Christmas Dinner The Food Lab: How to Cook a Perfect Prime Rib</li>
<li></li>
<li>This recipe works for prime rib roasts any size from 2 ribs to 6 ribs. Plan on 1 pound of bone-in roast per guest (each rib adds 1.5 to 2 pounds to the roast). For best results, use a dry-aged, prime grade or grass-fed roast.</li>
<li></li>
<li>To further improve the crust, allow it to air-dry, uncovered in the refrigerator on a rack overnight before roasting. Seasoning with salt up to a day in advance will help the seasoning penetrate the meat more deeply. If timing goes off and your roast is ready long before your guests are, the roast can be re-heated by placing in a 200°F oven for 45 minutes before continuing with step 2.</li>
</description>
<source>J. Kenji López-Alt</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Entree</category>
<category>Meats</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Perfect Quick-and-Easy French Toast</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>6 large eggs</li>
<li>4 tablespoons sugar, plus more for sprinkling</li>
<li>Pinch kosher salt</li>
<li>Pinch ground cinnamon</li>
<li>Pinch freshly grated nutmeg</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon vanilla extract</li>
<li>2 cups whole milk</li>
<li>4 tablespoons unsalted butter for the pan, plus more for serving</li>
<li>Eight (1/2-inch thick) slices white bread</li>
<li>Maple syrup, for serving</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Set a wire rack on a rimmed baking sheet in the oven and preheat to 200°F. If using very fresh, moist bread, arrange slices in a single layer on the rack and cook in oven, turning once, until lightly toasted, about 10 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Meanwhile, in a large mixing bowl, whisk together eggs, sugar, salt, cinnamon, nutmeg, and vanilla until thoroughly combined. Add milk and whisk to blend.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Heat 1 tablespoon butter in a large non-stick or cast iron skillet over medium heat, swirling skillet, until foaming subsides, about 5 minutes. Soak 2 slices of bread in egg bath, turning, until saturated. Add soaked bread to skillet and cook, swirling occasionally, until browned on bottom side, about 3 minutes. Sprinkle top side of bread with sugar, flip, and continue to cook, swirling occasionally, until browned on second side, about 3 minutes longer. Transfer French toast to the rack in the oven in a single layer to keep warm and repeat with remaining slices of bread and egg bath.</li>
<li></li>
<li>4.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serve French toast with pats of butter and maple syrup.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/04/perfect-quick-easy-french-toast.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Perfect_QuickandEasy_French_Toast.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/assets_c/2015/04/20140411-french-toast-recipe-09-edit-thumb-1500xauto-422515.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>serves 4</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description><li>This recipe appears in: Perfect Quick-and-Easy French Toast</li>
<li></li>
<li>French toast. [Photograph: J. Kenji Lopez-Alt.]</li>
<li></li>
<li>This easy recipe should be your go-to for basic French toast, designed for when you wake up in the morning and have a craving for French toast but haven't planned for it in advance. It uses only staples like bread, milk, and eggs, and pantry items like cinnamon, sugar, and nutmeg. The key to why it's so delicious and custardy is that the ratio of egg, milk, and sugar strikes the ideal balance—neither too wet and soggy nor too firm and eggy.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Why this recipe works:</li>
<li></li>
<li>By thoroughly testing batch after batch, we've found the ideal ratio for eggs, milk, and sugar.</li>
<li></li>
<li>A sprinkling of sugar on the surface of each piece creates a crisp caramel crunch.</li>
<li></li>
<li>About the Author: Daniel Gritzer is Culinary Director at Serious Eats. A former restaurant worker and itinerant farm laborer, he lives, and often eats, in Jackson Heights, Queens. Follow him at @dgritzer.</li>
</description>
<source>Daniel Gritzer</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Breakfast</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Peter Reinhart's Napoletana Pizza Dough</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>4 1/2 c unbleached high-gluten, bread, or all-purpose flour, chilled</li>
<li>1 3/4 t salt</li>
<li>1 t instant yeast</li>
<li>1/4 c olive oil</li>
<li>1 3/4 c water, ice cold (40°F)</li>
<li>Semolina flour or cornmeal for dusting</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Stir together the flour, salt, and instant yeast in a 4-quart bowl</li>
<li>(or in the bowl of an electric mixer). With a large metal spoon, stir</li>
<li>in the oil and the cold water until the flour is all absorbed (or mix</li>
<li>on low speed with the paddle attachment), If you are mixing by hand,</li>
<li>repeatedly dip one of your hands or the metal spoon into cold water</li>
<li>and use it, much like a dough hook, to work the dough vigorously into</li>
<li>a smooth mass while rotating the bowl in a circular motion with the</li>
<li>other hand. Reverse the circular motion a few times to develop the</li>
<li>gluten further. Do this for 5 to 7 minutes, or until the dough is</li>
<li>smooth and the ingredients are evenly distributed. If you are using an</li>
<li>electric mixer, switch to the dough hook and mix on medium speed for 5</li>
<li>to 7 minutes, or as long as it takes to create a smooth, sticky dough.</li>
<li>The dough should clear the sides of the bowl but stick to the bottom</li>
<li>of the bowl. If the dough is too wet and doesn't come off the sides of</li>
<li>the bowl, sprinkle in some more flour just until it clears the sides.</li>
<li>If it clears the bottom of the bowl, dribble in a tea- spoon or two of</li>
<li>cold water. The finished dough will be springy, elastic, and sticky,</li>
<li>not just tacky, and register 50 to 55F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>2. Sprinkle flour on the counter and transfer the dough to the</li>
<li>counter. Prepare a sheet pan by lining it with baking parchment and</li>
<li>misting the parchment with spray oil (or lightly oil the parchment).</li>
<li>Using a metal dough scraper, cut the dough into 6 equal pieces (or</li>
<li>larger if you are comfortable shaping large pizzas), You can dip the</li>
<li>scraper into the water between cuts to keep the dough from sticking to</li>
<li>it, Sprinkle flour over the dough. Make sure your hands are dry and</li>
<li>then flour them. Lift each piece and gently round it into a ball. If</li>
<li>the dough sticks to your hands, dip your hands into the flour again.</li>
<li>Transfer the dough balls to the sheet pan, Mist the dough generously</li>
<li>with spray oil and slip the pan into a food-grade plastic bag.</li>
<li></li>
<li>3. Put the pan into the refrigerator overnight to rest the dough, or</li>
<li>keep for up to 3 days. (Note: If you want to save some of the dough</li>
<li>for future baking, you can store the dough balls in a zippered freezer</li>
<li>bag. Dip each dough ball into a bowl that has a few tablespoons of oil</li>
<li>in it, rolling the dough in the oil, and then put each ball into a</li>
<li>separate bag. You can place the bags into the freezer for up to 3</li>
<li>months. Transfer them to the refrigerator the day before you plan to</li>
<li>make pizza.)</li>
<li></li>
<li>4. On the day you plan to make the pizza, remove the desired number of</li>
<li>dough balls from the refrigerator 2 hours before making the pizza.</li>
<li>Dust the counter with flour, and then mist the counter with spray oil.</li>
<li>Place the dough balls on top of the floured counter and sprinkle them</li>
<li>with flour; dust your hands with flour. Gently press the dough into</li>
<li>flat disks about 1/2 inch thick and 5 inches in diameter. Sprinkle the</li>
<li>dough with flour, mist it again with spray oil, and cover the dough</li>
<li>loosely with plastic wrap or a food-grade plastic bag. Let rest for 2</li>
<li>hours.</li>
<li></li>
<li>5. At least 45 minutes before making the pizza, place a baking stone</li>
<li>either on the floor of the oven (for gas ovens), or on a rack in the</li>
<li>lower third of the oven. Preheat the oven as hot as possible, up to</li>
<li>800F (most home ovens will go only to 500 to 550F, but some will go</li>
<li>higher). If you do not have a baking stone, you can use the back of a</li>
<li>sheet pan, but do not preheat the pan.</li>
<li></li>
<li>6. Generously dust a peel or the back of a sheet pan with semolina</li>
<li>flour or cornmeal. Make the pizzas one at a time. Dip your hands,</li>
<li>including the backs of your hands and knuckles, in flour and lift I</li>
<li>piece of dough by getting under it with a pastry scraper. Very gently</li>
<li>lay the dough across your fists and carefully stretch it by bouncing</li>
<li>the dough in a circular motion on your hands, carefully giving it a</li>
<li>little stretch with each bounce. If it begins to stick to your hands,</li>
<li>lay it down on the floured counter and reflour your hands, then</li>
<li>continue shaping it. Once the dough has expanded outward, move to a</li>
<li>full toss as shown on page 208. If you have trouble tossing the dough,</li>
<li>or if the dough keeps springing back, let it rest for 5 to 20 minutes</li>
<li>so the gluten can relax, and try again. You can also resort to using a</li>
<li>rolling pin, though this isn't as effective as the toss method.</li>
<li></li>
<li>7. When the dough is stretched out to your satisfaction (about 9 to 12</li>
<li>inches in diameter for a 6-ounce piece of dough), lay it on the peel</li>
<li>or pan, making sure there is enough semolina flour or cornmeal to</li>
<li>allow it to slide. Lightly top it with sauce and then with your other</li>
<li>top- pings, remembering that the best pizzas are topped with a less-</li>
<li>is-more philosophy. The American &quot;kitchen sink&quot; approach is</li>
<li>counterproductive, as it makes the crust more difficult to bake. A</li>
<li>few, usually no more than 3 or 4 toppings, including sauce and cheese</li>
<li>is sufficient.</li>
<li></li>
<li>8. Slide the topped pizza onto the stone (or bake directly on the</li>
<li>sheet pan) and close the door. Wait 2 minutes, then take a peek. If it</li>
<li>needs to be rotated 180 degrees for even baking, do so. The pizza</li>
<li>should take about 5 to 8 minutes to bake. If the top gets done before</li>
<li>the bottom, you will need to move the stone to a lower self before the</li>
<li>next round. if the bottom crisps before the cheese caramelizes, then</li>
<li>you will need to raise the stone for subsequent bakes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>9. Remove the pizza from the oven and transfer to a cutting board.</li>
<li>Wait 3 to 5 minutes before slicing and serving, to allow the cheese to</li>
<li>set slightly.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Makes six 6-ounce pizza crusts.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>MMF</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<category>Pizza</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Pizza Dough	</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 cup water (80°F – 90°F)</li>
<li>1 tbsp. honey or sugar or barley malt syrup</li>
<li>2 ¼ tsp extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>1 tsp salt</li>
<li>2 ¾ cups bread flour or white flour</li>
<li>1 tbsp bread machine yeast</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Measure ingredients into bread pan in the order listed.</li>
<li>2. Insert bread pan securely into baking chamber; close lid.</li>
<li>Plug unit into wall outlet.</li>
<li>3. Select Dough. Press the Start button.</li>
<li>4. The complete signal will sound when dough is done.</li>
<li>5. Using pot holders remove bread pan from baking chamber and</li>
<li>place dough on a lightly floured surface.</li>
<li>6. Invert a large mixing bowl over dough and let rest for 10 minutes.</li>
<li>7. Divide dough in half. Set one half aside and keep covered. Lightly</li>
<li>brush 2 large pizza pans with olive oil and sprinkle with cornmeal;</li>
<li>set aside.</li>
<li>8. On lightly floured surface roll out half of dough to fit prepared pan.</li>
<li>Top with desired topping ingredients such as sauce, cheese and</li>
<li>vegetables. Bake in a preheated oven at 425ºF for 20 minutes or</li>
<li>until edges are golden and cheese is bubbling.</li>
<li>9. Repeat with remaining dough.</li>
</recipetext>
<url></url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>
			2
		</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments><li>For Foccacia: Brush 15½ x 10½ inch jelly roll pan with olive oil and</li>
<li>sprinkle with cornmeal. Roll out dough on a lightly floured surface and</li>
<li>fit into pan. Cover loosely with plastic wrap and set aside until doubled</li>
<li>in size (about 40 minutes). Using oiled fingertips, press indentations</li>
<li>into dough about ½-inch deep and about 1-inch apart. Drizzle with</li>
<li>3 to 4 tbsp. olive oil and sprinkle with 1 tsp. coarse or sea salt, ¾ cup</li>
<li>freshly grated Parmesan, Romano and Asiago cheese and 1/3 cup</li>
<li>mixture of fresh chopped herbs such as parsley, rosemary, basil and</li>
<li>oregano. Bake in preheated oven at 425ºF until crust is golden and</li>
<li>bread is puffed (about 20 minutes).</li>
</comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Pizza</category>
<category>Italian</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Potato Chips</title>
<preptime>30M</preptime>
<cooktime>5M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 tablespoon vegetable oil</li>
<li>1 potato, sliced paper thin (peel optional)</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt, or to taste</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Pour the vegetable oil into a plastic bag (a produce bag works well). Add the potato slices, and shake to coat.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Coat a large dinner plate lightly with oil or cooking spray. Arrange potato slices in a single layer on the dish.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cook in the microwave for 3 to 5 minutes, or until lightly browned (if not browned, they will not become crisp). Times will vary depending on the power of your microwave. Remove chips from plate, and toss with salt (or other seasonings). Let cool. Repeat process with the remaining potato slices. You will not need to keep oiling the plate.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Kitchen-Friendly View</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/potato-chips/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Potato_Chips.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/250x250/00/09/36/93653.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutritional Information</li>
<li></li>
<li>Potato Chips</li>
<li></li>
<li>Serving Size: 1/4 of a recipe</li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 4</li>
<li>Amount Per Serving</li>
<li>Calories: 80</li>
<li>Calories from Fat: 31</li>
<li></li>
<li>% Daily Value *</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Fat 3.5g 5 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Saturated Fat 0.5g 3 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol 0mg 0 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium 295mg 12 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Potassium 214mg 6 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Total Carbohydrates 11.6g 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Dietary Fiber 1.1g 4 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein 1.2g 2 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>** Sugars 0g</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin A 0 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Vitamin C 12 %</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calcium</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>35M</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Make your own potato chips using your microwave. A tasty and easy alternative to store-bought potato chips (not to mention economical)! A mandoline would make slicing the potato into paper thin slices a breeze.&quot;</description>
<source>Jessica</source>
<video>http://allrecipes.com/video/4260/potato-chips/detail.aspx</video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Snacks</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Rice</title>
<preptime>5 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>25 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1½ c. long-grain white rice, jasmine rice, or basmati rice</li>
<li>2 c. water</li>
<li></li>
<li></li>
<li>½ cup rice</li>
<li>1 cup water</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Measure out 1 ½ cup of jasmine rice and pour it into a saucepan that has a tight-fitting lid. Move over to the sink and run some room-temperature water over the top of the rice until it covers the rice by about an inch. Use your fingers to swirl the rice and water around the pan. Drain the water off of the rice using a fine mesh sieve or through your hand if you don’t have one. Repeat the process of adding water, swirling, and draining three more times.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Once you've finished, measure 2 cups of water and add it to the pot. Stir the rice as you add in the water, but do NOT stir it again once you've turned the heat on - ever.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Set the pot over medium-heat and patiently wait as it comes to a boil. Let it boil until the water level drops below the level of the rice (the rice will be peeking through the top). Turn the heat down to the lowest setting possible, place the kitchen towel over the top of the pot, and cover the rice with the pot’s lid. Bring the edges of the towel up and twist around the handle of the lid so they aren't dangling down near the heat element.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Set a timer for 15 minutes and walk away. Once that timer goes off, turn the heat off entirely and let the rice sit for 10 more minutes before taking off the lid. After 10 minutes, remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork. Serve hot.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://thewanderlustkitchen.com/how-to-cook-perfect-rice/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Rice.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://thewanderlustkitchen.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Perfect-Jasmine-Rice-9-682x1024.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>5 cups</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>30 mins</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>The Wanderlust Kitchen</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Sides</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Roast Beef with Roasted Potatoes &amp; Carrots</title>
<preptime>15 minutes</preptime>
<cooktime>1¼ hours</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 Beef Eye Round Roast, about 3 lbs</li>
<li>2 Tbsp Olive Oil, divided</li>
<li>3 Tbsp Beef Seasoning (Lawry)</li>
<li>2 lb Red Potatoes, cut into 1½&quot; cubes</li>
<li>2 lb Carrots, peeled with tops or Baby Carrots.</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>1. Preheat oven to 375°.</li>
<li>Brush 1Tbsp. of oil over roast, choosing completely.</li>
<li>2. Sprinkle on 2Tbsp. of seasoning, then place roast on a rack in a shallow, foil-lined roasting pan.</li>
<li>3. Blend remaining oil and seasoning in a large bowl. Add potatoes and carrots; toss to coat well. Arrange vegetables on rack around roast.</li>
<li>4. Place roast in oven on center rack. Cook until a meat thermometer registers 135° ( medium rare), about 1 hr 15 min.</li>
<li>5. remove from oven. transfer to a warm platter and tent with foil. let stand 10 min before craving.</li>
</recipetext>
<url></url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>12 Servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Entree</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Shepherd's Pie - Alton Brown</title>
<preptime>0H45M</preptime>
<cooktime>0H45M</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>For the potatoes:</li>
<li>1 1/2 pounds russet potatoes</li>
<li>1/4 cup half-and-half</li>
<li>2 ounces unsalted butter</li>
<li>3/4 teaspoon kosher salt</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper</li>
<li>1 egg yolk</li>
<li>For the meat filling:</li>
<li>2 tablespoons canola oil</li>
<li>1 cup chopped onion</li>
<li>2 carrots, peeled and diced small</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, minced</li>
<li>1 1/2 pounds ground lamb</li>
<li>1 teaspoon kosher salt</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper</li>
<li>2 tablespoons all-purpose flour</li>
<li>2 teaspoons tomato paste</li>
<li>1 cup chicken broth</li>
<li>1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce</li>
<li>2 teaspoons freshly chopped rosemary leaves</li>
<li>1 teaspoon freshly chopped thyme leaves</li>
<li>1/2 cup fresh or frozen corn kernels</li>
<li>1/2 cup fresh or frozen English peas</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Peel the potatoes and cut into 1/2-inch dice. Place in a medium saucepan and cover with cold water. Set over high heat, cover and bring to a boil. Once boiling, uncover, decrease the heat to maintain a simmer and cook until tender and easily crushed with tongs, approximately 10 to 15 minutes. Place the half-and-half and butter into a microwave-safe container and heat in the microwave until warmed through, about 35 seconds. Drain the potatoes in a colander and then return to the saucepan. Mash the potatoes and then add the half and half, butter, salt and pepper and continue to mash until smooth. Stir in the yolk until well combined.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>While the potatoes are cooking, prepare the filling. Place the canola oil into a 12-inch saute pan and set over medium high heat. Once the oil shimmers, add the onion and carrots and saute just until they begin to take on color, approximately 3 to 4 minutes. Add the garlic and stir to combine. Add the lamb, salt and pepper and cook until browned and cooked through, approximately 3 minutes. Sprinkle the meat with the flour and toss to coat, continuing to cook for another minute. Add the tomato paste, chicken broth, Worcestershire, rosemary, thyme, and stir to combine. Bring to a boil, reduce the heat to low, cover and simmer slowly 10 to 12 minutes or until the sauce is thickened slightly.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the corn and peas to the lamb mixture and spread evenly into an 11 by 7-inch glass baking dish. Top with the mashed potatoes, starting around the edges to create a seal to prevent the mixture from bubbling up and smooth with a rubber spatula. Place on a parchment lined half sheet pan on the middle rack of the oven and bake for 25 minutes or just until the potatoes begin to brown. Remove to a cooling rack for at least 15 minutes before serving.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Recipe courtesy Alton Brown, 2008</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/alton-brown/shepherds-pie-recipe2.html</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Shepherds_Pie__Alton_Brown.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://foodnetwork.sndimg.com/content/dam/images/food/fullset/2011/7/26/2/EA1206_shepherds-pie_s4x3.jpg.rend.sni12col.landscape.jpeg</imageurl>
<quantity>8 servings</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>1H30M</totaltime>
<description></description>
<source>Alton Brown</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Entree</category>
<category>Irish</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Slow cooker Meatballs and Marinara</title>
<preptime>1/2 hour</preptime>
<cooktime>4 hours</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>Onion Mixture:</li>
<li>2 tb olive oil</li>
<li>2 onions, chopped fine</li>
<li>6 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>1 tb dried oregano</li>
<li>1/2 t red pepper flakes</li>
<li>1/4 t salt</li>
<li>Marinara:</li>
<li>1/2 c red wine</li>
<li>Meatballs:</li>
<li>4 oz Italian sausage, casings removed</li>
<li>2 oz mozzarella cheese, shredded (1/2 cup)</li>
<li>1 oz parmesan cheese, grated (1/2 cup)</li>
<li>2 lg eggs</li>
<li>2 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>3/4 t salt</li>
<li>lb 85% lean ground beef</li>
<li>3 tb heavy cream</li>
<li>1 oz parmesan cheese, grated (1/2 cup)</li>
<li>2 tb finely chopped fresh basil</li>
<li>salt</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preparation Time: 1/2 hour</li>
<li>Link: http://www.savorysimple.net/slow-cooker-meatballs-and-marinara-americas-test-kitchen/</li>
<li></li>
<li>1-6 oz can tomato past</li>
<li>2-28 oz cans crushed tomatoes</li>
<li></li>
<li>For the onion mixture</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. Heat oil in a Dutch oven over medium-high heat until shimmering.</li>
<li>Add onions, tomato paste, garlic, oregano,</li>
<li></li>
<li>pepper flakes, and salt and cook until softened and lightly browned,</li>
<li>about 8 to 10 minutes. Transfer half of the</li>
<li></li>
<li>onion mixture to a large bowl and set aside.</li>
<li></li>
<li>For the marinara</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. Add wine to the remaining onion mixture in pot and cook until</li>
<li>slightly thickened, about 2 minutes. Stir in</li>
<li></li>
<li>tomatoes, then transfer to a slow cooker.</li>
<li></li>
<li>For the meatballs</li>
<li></li>
<li>1. Add sausage, mozzarella, parmesan, eggs, garlic and salt to bowl</li>
<li>with reserved onion mixture. Mash with a</li>
<li></li>
<li>potato masher until smooth. Add beef and cream to bowl and knead with</li>
<li>hands until well combined. Lightly</li>
<li></li>
<li>shape mixture into 2-inch round meatballs (about 12 total). Microwave</li>
<li>meatballs on large plate until fat renders</li>
<li></li>
<li>and meatballs are firm, 4 to 7 minutes. Nestle meatballs into slow</li>
<li>cooker, discarding rendered fat. Cover and</li>
<li></li>
<li>cook until meatballs are tender and sauce is slightly thickened, 4 to</li>
<li>5 hours on low. Let meatballs and sauce</li>
<li></li>
<li>settle for 5 minutes, then skim fat from surface and stir in Parmesan</li>
<li>and basil. Season with salt to taste. Serve.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Source: America's Test Kitchen</li>
<li></li>
<li>Microwave the meatballs on a large plate or in a casserole dish to</li>
<li>contain the rendering fat. This recipe makes</li>
<li></li>
<li>enough to sauce 1½ pounds of pasta.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>MMF</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<category>Italian</category>
<category>Entree</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>The Best Creole/Cajun Seasoning Mix</title>
<preptime>5M</preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>2 tablespoons onion powder</li>
<li>2 tablespoons garlic powder</li>
<li>2 tablespoons dried oregano</li>
<li>2 tablespoons dried basil</li>
<li>1 tablespoon dried thyme</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh ground black pepper</li>
<li>1 tablespoon white pepper (or 2 use tablespoons black pepper)</li>
<li>3 teaspoons cayenne pepper</li>
<li>5 tablespoons paprika</li>
<li>4 -5 tablespoons seasoning salt (I use Hy's seasoned salt for this but Lawry's is good also!)</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Mix all ingredients in a glass jar.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Store in the refrigerator to keep the spices fresh.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Shake the jar before using.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/the-best-creole-cajun-seasoning-mix-186029</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/The_Best_CreoleCajun_Seasoning_Mix.png</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://img.sndimg.com/food/image/upload/w_614,h_461,c_fit/v1/img/recipes/18/60/29/picW0iKO6.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>1 (5 g)</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 16.7 Calories from Fat 3 20% Total Fat 0.4 g 0% Saturated Fat 0.1 g 0% Cholesterol 0 mg 0% Sodium 3.1 mg 0% Total Carbohydrate 3.6 g 1% Dietary Fiber 1.5 g 5% Sugars 0.3 g 1% Protein 0.8 g 1%</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>5M</totaltime>
<description>Move over Emeril!... you will never purchase Creole or Cajun seasoning again once you taste this one --- I have searched for the longest time to find the best seasoning blend, this is it! --- four tablespoons of seasoned salt will not be overly-salty if you prefer a more salty taste then add in some white salt --- this makes a fair amount of seasoning, just store in a tightly-sealed glass jar in the refrigerator to use in ground beef recipes, soups, or stews, homemade pasta sauce recipes, or use it to season roasts, chickens, pork, beef, I use it on just about everything! If you like extreme spice then increase the cayenne up to 4-5 teaspoons. This makes a great gift for a spice-lover!</description>
<source>Kittencal@recipezazz</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Ingredients</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Traditional Irish Shepherd’s Pie</title>
<preptime></preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>Meat Mixture:</li>
<li>1 1/2 lb lamb or beef (cubed or ground is fine)</li>
<li>1 lg sweet onion, diced</li>
<li>3 lg carrots, peeled and diced</li>
<li>4 cloves garlic, minced</li>
<li>2 tb butter</li>
<li>3 tb flour</li>
<li>1 c Guinness stout</li>
<li>1 c red wine</li>
<li>1 c beef broth</li>
<li>1 tb Worcestershire sauce</li>
<li>2 t dried basil</li>
<li>2 t dried oregano</li>
<li>2 t dried sage</li>
<li>1 c frozen peas, defrosted</li>
<li>Potatoes:</li>
<li>2 lb russet potatoes, peeled and cut into equal sized pieces</li>
<li>4 tb butter</li>
<li>1 1/2 c grated white cheddar cheese</li>
<li>1/4 c milk</li>
<li>1/4 c fresh parsley, chopped</li>
<li>1/3 c chives, chopped</li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preheat oven to 350.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place potatoes in a large pot and cover with water. Bring to a boil</li>
<li>and cook until potatoes are</li>
<li></li>
<li>fork-tender, about 15 minutes. Drain well and return to pot to remove</li>
<li>any excess moisture.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Meanwhile, brown beef or lamb in a large dutch oven over medium heat.</li>
<li>Drain off any excess</li>
<li></li>
<li>fat. Add onions, carrots and garlic, and sauté until softened. Add</li>
<li>butter, stir until melted.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sprinkle flour over meat and veggies, stirring to coat. Cook 1 minute.</li>
<li>Deglaze pan with</li>
<li></li>
<li>Guinness, red wine, and beef broth. Bring to a simmer, then reduce</li>
<li>heat to medium low. Add</li>
<li></li>
<li>Worcestershire sauce and spices, simmer about 15 minutes, or until</li>
<li>carrots are tender. Add</li>
<li></li>
<li>peas, and season mixture to taste with salt and pepper. Simmer until</li>
<li>mixture has thickened.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Once potatoes are drained, stir in butter and milk and mash until</li>
<li>consistency is smooth (add a</li>
<li></li>
<li>little more milk if necessary). Stir in cheese, parsley and chives.</li>
<li>Season with salt and pepper.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Pour thickened meat mixture into greased casserole dish (I used an</li>
<li>oval one, smaller than a</li>
<li></li>
<li>9×13). Spoon potatoes gently over the top of the meat mixture, making</li>
<li>irregular peaks with the</li>
<li></li>
<li>back of your spoon. Bake at 350 for 20-30 minutes, or until potatoes</li>
<li>are golden brown and</li>
<li></li>
<li>edges are bubbly.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>MMF</url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity></quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<category>Irish</category>
<category>Entree</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Truly Golden Crunchy Baked Chicken Tenders (Minimum Mess)</title>
<preptime>15 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>10 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1¾ cups panko breadcrumbs (Note 1)</li>
<li>1 tbsp olive oil</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>1 tbsp mayonnaise (I use whole egg)</li>
<li>1½ tbsp dijon mustard (or any other mustard of choice)</li>
<li>2 tbsp flour</li>
<li>½ tsp salt</li>
<li>Black pepper</li>
<li>500g/1lb chicken tenderloins (or chicken breast cut into ⅔&quot; / 1.5cm thick slices, lengthwise)</li>
<li>Oil spray</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preheat oven to 200C/390F.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place a rack on a baking tray (not critical but bakes more evenly).</li>
<li></li>
<li>Heat olive oil in a large fry pan over medium high heat. Add the breadcrumbs and sauté for 3 minutes until golden brown. Keep it moving otherwise it will brown unevenly. Remove from heat and immediately transfer to a bowl. Allow to cool slightly.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Place the Batter ingredients in a bowl and whisk with a fork until combined.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add the chicken into the Batter and toss to coat.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Pick up a piece of chicken with your left hand and place it into the panko bowl.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Use your right hand to sprinkle some breadcrumbs onto one end of the chicken, then pick up that end of the chicken and turn it over. Pat down gently to press the breadcrumbs onto the chicken, then transfer onto baking tray.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Repeat with remaining chicken.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Spray lightly with oil. Bake for 10 minutes.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Remove from oven and serve immediately, with Ranch Dipping Sauce (Note 2) and sprinkled with fresh parsley, if desired.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.recipetineats.com/truly-golden-crunchy-baked-chicken-tenders-less-mess/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Truly_Golden_Crunchy_Baked_Chicken_Tenders_Minimum_Mess.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://cdn2.recipetineats.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Crumbed-Chicken_680px_High-Angle1.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>3</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>25 mins</totaltime>
<description>This is how I make crumbed chicken in the oven that comes out a lovely golden brown (no bits of white breadcrumbs) without the chicken overcooking. It's extra crunchy AND there's minimum crumbing-mess! I served this with a Ranch Dipping Sauce (Note 2) but the chicken is juicy and has plenty of flavour in the crumb so a dipping sauce isn't essential. Some people would consider that this recipe is enough for 4 people. I think it's enough for 3 as a meal. :)</description>
<source>Nagi | RecipeTin Eats</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Poultry</category>
<category>Entree</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>Whole Wheat Pizza Dough</title>
<preptime>
			2 hours
		</preptime>
<cooktime>
			15 minutes
		</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 c warm water (100-110⁰F)</li>
<li>1 Tbsp olive oil</li>
<li>1 tsp salt</li>
<li>1 Tbsp sugar</li>
<li>2 1/2 c whole wheat flour</li>
<li>1 Tbsp vital wheat gluten, (It will make for a chewier and less dense crust)</li>
<li>2 1/4 tsp active dry yeast</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>In a Bread Machine</li>
<li>Add crust ingredients (in the order listed) to the bread pan of your bread machine. Process according the manufacturer’s instructions for the dough setting. (Don’t be afraid to open the lid to check on it. The dough should come together to a nice, soft and slightly tacky ball after a little knead time. If the dough looks too moist, add more flour a teaspoon at a time. If it looks too dry, add warm water a bit at a time.)</li>
<li>When the dough is done, remove it from the bread machine.</li>
<li></li>
<li>In a Stand Mixer</li>
<li>Mix all ingredients well with a dough hook for 5-7 minutes, until a nice elastic ball forms. Cover and place in a warm place to rise until doubled (1 hour). Knock back the dough and let rise, covered, a second time, until you are ready to make your pizza.</li>
</recipetext>
<url></url>
<imagepath></imagepath>
<imageurl></imageurl>
<quantity>
			4
		</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition></nutrition>
<comments>Yield: 1 (14&quot;) pizza</comments>
<totaltime></totaltime>
<description></description>
<source></source>
<video></video>
<category>Pizza</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>World's Best Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
<preptime>15 mins</preptime>
<cooktime>12 mins</cooktime>
<ingredient><li>3⁄4 cup white sugar</li>
<li>1 cup brown sugar</li>
<li>1 cup butter, softened</li>
<li>1 tablespoon vanilla</li>
<li>2 large eggs, slightly beaten</li>
<li>3 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>3⁄4 teaspoon baking soda</li>
<li>3⁄4 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>3 cups semi-sweet chocolate chips</li>
<li>1 cup walnuts, chopped or 1 cup pecans</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext><li>Preheat oven to 350 degrees.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cream sugars and butter.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Add vanilla and eggs and mix well.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Combine dry ingredients together and gradually add to creamed mixture.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Stir in chips and nuts.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Roll into 1 1/4&quot; balls and place on non-stick cookie sheets, about 2&quot; apart.</li>
<li></li>
<li>Bake for 10 to 12 minutes.</li>
</recipetext>
<url>http://www.food.com/recipe/worlds-best-chocolate-chip-cookies-26849</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Worlds_Best_Chocolate_Chip_Cookies.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://img.sndimg.com/food/image/upload/w_614,h_461,c_fit/v1/img/recipes/26/84/9/picjempjo.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>6 dozen cookies</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Serving Size: 1 (23 g)</li>
<li></li>
<li>Servings Per Recipe: 72</li>
<li></li>
<li>Amount Per Serving % Daily Value Calories 108 Calories from Fat 53 49% Total Fat 5.9 g 9% Saturated Fat 3 g 15% Cholesterol 12 mg 3% Sodium 63.6 mg 2% Total Carbohydrate 13.8 g 4% Dietary Fiber 0.7 g 2% Sugars 9 g 35% Protein 1.3 g 2%</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>27mins</totaltime>
<description>There's not much to say...the name says it all. These are better than Toll House in our book. I make these every Christmas and it is my standard Chocolate Chip Cookie.</description>
<source>Karen=^..^=</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Baking</category>
<category>Dessert</category>
<category>Snacks</category>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<title>World's Easiest Bread Machine Pizza Dough</title>
<preptime>2 h</preptime>
<cooktime></cooktime>
<ingredient><li>1 cup warm water</li>
<li>3 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>3 tablespoons white sugar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon sea salt</li>
<li>3 cups all-purpose flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon minced garlic</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried oregano</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried basil</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon ground black pepper</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried cilantro</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon paprika</li>
<li>2 1/4 teaspoons active dry yeast</li>
</ingredient>
<recipetext>Put the water, olive oil, sugar, sea salt, flour, garlic, oregano, basil, black pepper, cilantro, paprika, and dry yeast into the pan of a bread machine individually in order as listed. Select Dough cycle; press Start. Let dough rest 5 to 30 minutes before using; the longer it rests, the thicker the crust.</recipetext>
<url>http://allrecipes.com/recipe/222866/worlds-easiest-bread-machine-pizza-dough/</url>
<imagepath>/storage/emulated/0/MyCookBook/images/Worlds_Easiest_Bread_Machine_Pizza_Dough.jpg</imagepath>
<imageurl>http://images.media-allrecipes.com/userphotos/720x405/2947262.jpg</imageurl>
<quantity>4</quantity>
<rating>0</rating>
<nutrition><li>Nutrition</li>
<li></li>
<li>Calories:</li>
<li></li>
<li>476 kcal</li>
<li></li>
<li>24%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Fat:</li>
<li></li>
<li>11.2 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>17%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Carbs:</li>
<li></li>
<li>82.3g</li>
<li></li>
<li>27%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Protein:</li>
<li></li>
<li>10.7 g</li>
<li></li>
<li>21%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Cholesterol:</li>
<li></li>
<li>0 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>0%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Sodium:</li>
<li></li>
<li>445 mg</li>
<li></li>
<li>18%</li>
<li></li>
<li>Based on a 2,000 calorie diet</li>
<li></li>
<li>See full nutrition</li>
</nutrition>
<comments></comments>
<totaltime>2 h 5 m</totaltime>
<description>&quot;Borrowed from a handful of other pizza dough recipes and tweaked to yield a tasty, thick crust using a bread machine. If you use a pizza stone, sprinkle it with cornmeal before placing the pizza on it to help keep it from sticking. Feel free to try different spices if you don't like any of the ones in this recipe.&quot;</description>
<source>soxinsc</source>
<video></video>
<lang>en</lang>
<category>Pizza</category>
</recipe>

</cookbook>
